<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog</id>
    <title>Graveyard World Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-07-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Graveyard World Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sands of the First Sin Chapter 1: The Ifrit]]></title>
        <id>The-Sands-of-the-First-Sin-Chapter-1-The-Ifrit</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/The-Sands-of-the-First-Sin-Chapter-1-The-Ifrit"/>
        <updated>2022-07-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party wakes in Last Gift after two months on the road, crossing the vast desert of Oria’s Vigil, delivering forty mules, lead by the caravan master Yorvis Heue, from Terak Tel to a mine far from civilisation.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party wakes in Last Gift after two months on the road, crossing the vast desert of Oria’s Vigil, delivering forty mules, lead by the caravan master Yorvis Heue, from Terak Tel to a mine far from civilisation.</p><p>The party quickly discovers an issue – no local guides will take Yorvis any further east, due to a line of cairns laid across the savanah. The village elder, a gnoll by the name of Rhyser Rotahn, informs the party that her lover and the villages best tracker, Kurk Roteh, has gone missing on the other side of the cairns. As the party will be using Last Gift as their base of operations for the foreseeable future, they agree to track down Kurk as a portion of thier material contribution in exchange for room and board.</p><p>Travelling east, they find the cairns just as the sun sets. After distrupting one of the cairns, the party observes constructs, smoke-filled suits of armour, both humanoid and bestial, and eventually draw the attention of the intelligence controlling them, a green fire watching from a tower in the distance.</p><p>The party parleys with the intelligence, and Orgmo agrees to the prisoner transfer with Kurk – “someone must burn the books,” says the fire, though it does not care who. Orgmo is taken, but leaves a trail for his hound to follow, and the party trails them at a distance.</p><p>Cresting a hill, Orgmo observes he is being taken to an ancient structure carved into the side of a high sandstone cliff. Observing the murals and cross referencing with a local legend, Orgmo realises this is the home of an ifrit, chained into servitude by the old empire and clearly recently reawakened.</p><p>No-pockets and Ursula follow Orgmo into the ruins, sneaking their way towards a vast library. As Kurk emerges from the depths, Ursula creates a distraction by dislodging a massive rock, giving No-Pockets time to pull Kurk to saftely and Orgmo to escape to the upper levels, where he comes face to face with the ifrit, 10 feet tall and wrapped in billowing green fire.</p><p>Ursula strikes the demon in the head with an arrow, but the two are both overpowered by the creatues powerful flaming attacks.</p><p>No-Pockets uses this opportunity to enter the library, clearly warded from the ifrit, (and answering the question of why it needed mortal servants to procure books), which the ifrit has been ritually burning to create new smoke servants. Quickly locating and stealing the most expensive looking tome, locked away in an ornate box, No-Pockets inadvertantly lowers the wards protecting the space.</p><p>The ifrit, suddenly aware of this, makes its way back to the library, where No-Pockets stabs it in the back with a dagger.</p><p>Simultaniously, Ursula and Orgmo break through a collapsed doorway into daylight, and move a mirror to flood the library with daylight, apparently banishing the creature in a flash of light, leaving Kurk rescued, the library, and the eastern plains, safe for further exploration.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 36: Meet the Crew]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-36-Meet-the-Crew</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-36-Meet-the-Crew"/>
        <updated>2019-11-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 35: Storm of Vengeance]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-35-Storm-of-Vengeance</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-35-Storm-of-Vengeance"/>
        <updated>2019-10-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 34: Plans]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-34-Plans</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-34-Plans"/>
        <updated>2019-08-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 33: Daylight]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-33-Daylight</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-33-Daylight"/>
        <updated>2019-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 32: Coral, Caldra, and Gurgle]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-32-Coral,-Caldra,-and-Gurgle</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-32-Coral,-Caldra,-and-Gurgle"/>
        <updated>2019-07-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 31: Lightbringer]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-31-Lightbringer</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-31-Lightbringer"/>
        <updated>2019-06-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Days earlier, Urllex finds her way into her aunt Urzoth’s tomb, to find her half alive and almost completely encased in a living prison of sea-life. Time accelerates as Urzoth speaks, as she is almost a statue at this point.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Days earlier, Urllex finds her way into her aunt Urzoth’s tomb, to find her half alive and almost completely encased in a living prison of sea-life. Time accelerates as Urzoth speaks, as she is almost a statue at this point.</p><p>Urzoth berates Urllex for coming to late, and not growing into the paladin that she had hoped for. The two argue , and Urzoth accepts that Urllex will always be a hot-headed wanderer.</p><p>Urzoth tells the story of how she came to be like this – fifty years ago, Urzoth and Kharl the Elder became aware of a darkness threatening every ocean. The ancient elven god of the sea, <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/deep-sashelas">Deep Sashelas</a>, had become corrupted, devolving into a mindless, all consuming demonic entity. On the behest of their gods, the pair sought out a party consisting of Gundren Rockseeker, Lillen Shadowcloak, Kaz and Tock, and stole Sashelas seven gifts from the demon <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/Kyuss/new">Kyuss</a>.</p><p>Using these, they sealed Deep Sashelas away, creating the Maelstrom, the same event that destroyed Castien and smashed the elven city into the Beast Coast. Urzoth refers to this event as her penance.</p><p>The party separated, each taking one of the gifts with them (leaving the seventh, the black, which was later stolen by Xullraen). Urzoth accepted the curse of Life, and as such she is slowly being consumed by the sea, but has accepted this. She tells Urllex that through this acceptance, Urzoth will become the seed of a new god, that will be able to fight Sashelas in ascension and defeat them for good.</p><p>Urzoth warns Urllex that in seven months, a great tide will come, and the Maelstrom will not be able to contain Sashelas. Before then, they must gather what gifts they can and go to face Seshales in the material plane.</p><p>Urllex is gifted a Cloak of the Kraken and sent on her way. Sensing Kharl and Varyk’s location, she swims from Urzoth’s tomb to the underdark, bursting out of the water just as Kharl is being introduced to the goblin Hogstrom.</p><p>The party is led into the orc and goblin controlled caves, revealling that their attack against the Drow had gone badly, but they still had strength behind them, including a tame Otyugh, ‘Spike.’ Entering another section of ruined city, the party is presented to the goblin seer Kugs. Kugs welcomes Urllexin as ‘Lightbringer,’ but reveals that many orcs wear that mantle, and that they rule as a collective, weirding Urllex out. The party learns that the orcs, using Lightbringer, had freed themselves from Drow control and were in the process of escaping to the surface, but were cut off by Xullraen’s forces above.</p><p>Kharl promises to perform a scrying ceremony in the morning and goes away to prepare. Urllex meditates on her position, as Kharl goes looking for somewhere to offload his bounty of coins, stumbling upon Debope the Wheel’d, this time at an establishment labelled as ‘Goblin Have.’ There, he trades some coins and belongings for a retractable pole and a golden mask.</p><p>Returning to the orc guest house, the party settles in for the night.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 30: Into the Underdark]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-30-Into-the-Underdark</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-30-Into-the-Underdark"/>
        <updated>2019-06-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kharl, Varyk and Dakarai ready themselves to go further into the caves, the way behind closed to them. In the night, Kharl wakes to see Dakarai staring deep into an orb they are holding – in the morning, he is gone. After waiting for a time, Varyk and Kharl make their way into the darkness below, Varyk leading with Kharl in tow, tied by a rope.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kharl, Varyk and Dakarai ready themselves to go further into the caves, the way behind closed to them. In the night, Kharl wakes to see Dakarai staring deep into an orb they are holding – in the morning, he is gone. After waiting for a time, Varyk and Kharl make their way into the darkness below, Varyk leading with Kharl in tow, tied by a rope.</p><p>Making their way through natural caverns, they find that they are sealed <em>in</em>, a warning to drow from the order side saying not to go any further. The pair surmise that the drow they have fought so far came from below, not above.</p><p>Talking their way past a pair of drow sentries, spooked by the early resurrection of Xullraen happening in an adjacent sanctum, the pair make their way out of the temple complex and into the ruins of an underground city. Cautiously making their way through the ruins, the party stumbles upon the nest of a chimera. After a brief exchange, Kharl banishes the Chimera and claims its hoard – 75kgs of copper and silver coins.</p><p>Stumbling upon a much larger part of the ruined city, and weighed down with treasure, Kharl hides while Varyk scouts. Varyk finds the reason for the lightly protected inner sanctum – the drow are being attacked by orcs and goblins to the south. Using the attack as a cover, Kharl, masquerading as a prisoner and Varyk talk their way through the front lines and out of the drow city.</p><p>Finding their way to an underground river, Varyk is approached by a goblin that claims to know the party, as Kharl gave these orcs Lightbringer back in the Spellforge. Kharl takes the goblins hand and asks to be led to their seer, Kugs, the blind goblin.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 28: The Drowned Tower]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-28-The-Drowned-Tower</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-28-The-Drowned-Tower"/>
        <updated>2019-05-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dakarai asks Kharl to destroy him so that he can experience another vision. Kharl obliges, and Dakarai finds himself in a prison cell underground. He finds his way into a warded prison, and ends up face to face with Naivara, in his true body. She tells him that Xullraen, the drow she had been staying with, has betrayed her, and intends to absorb the sand curse from her in a dark ritual that very night, and that she has done the same with another curse the night before. She gives Dakarai clues to his whereabouts, and he returns to his own body.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dakarai asks Kharl to destroy him so that he can experience another vision. Kharl obliges, and Dakarai finds himself in a prison cell underground. He finds his way into a warded prison, and ends up face to face with Naivara, in his true body. She tells him that Xullraen, the drow she had been staying with, has betrayed her, and intends to absorb the sand curse from her in a dark ritual that very night, and that she has done the same with another curse the night before. She gives Dakarai clues to his whereabouts, and he returns to his own body.</p><p>Putting together clues with the help of their kenku companions (Cartwheel, Noose, Crash and Squeal), the party makes their way through torrential rain to find the Drowned Tower, northwest of Old Castien. The party seeks out and finds the tower, and begins to descend. They make their way down, level by level, fighting oozes and cultists, before coming face to face with Naivara once more. Naivara makes peace with Dakarai, who vows to help her escape her fate trapped in Dakarai’s body, and the two merge once more.</p><p>Descending deeper into the sunken tower, the party finds themselves in an ancient temple to a god of war, crudely transformed into a altar to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/deep-sashelas">Deep Sashelas</a>. Praying before it is Xullraen, who turns to fight the party. She is quickly defeated, surprised, but in her defeat, she reveals a new power, transforming into an enormous, black hydra…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 29: The Hydra]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-29-The-Hydra</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-29-The-Hydra"/>
        <updated>2019-05-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kharl and Varyk corner the Hydra with a sleet and firestorm, preventing it from moving. Varyk keeps up the pressure while Kharl and Dakarai clamber up the statue of Bahall towards an orb that is clearly channeling Xullraen’s ritual. While lashing hydra heads snap at them from all angles, Kharl manages to to seize the orb and shatter it between his hands in an act of brute strength.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kharl and Varyk corner the Hydra with a sleet and firestorm, preventing it from moving. Varyk keeps up the pressure while Kharl and Dakarai clamber up the statue of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/Bahall/new">Bahall</a> towards an orb that is clearly channeling Xullraen’s ritual. While lashing hydra heads snap at them from all angles, Kharl manages to to seize the orb and shatter it between his hands in an act of brute strength.</p><p>Though the ritual is stalled, Varyk is pulled underwater by an unseen enemy, but is able to keep concentration up on his fire spell. Dakarai manages to free Varyk, and Kharl, eye to eye with the hydra, destroys it with his lightning breath, dispelling the form and revealing Xullraen, broken and dying.</p><p>Xullraen is stabilised by Kharl and taken prisoner. She reveals that she had already completed half of the ritual she needed to, and that ‘three of the seven’ were now consumed by her god, and that they needed only one more to tip the balance in her favour. As the temple collapses around the party, she teleports beneath a landslide, killing her and allowing her to reincarnate.</p><p>Trapped underground, the party finds a hidden staircase below the statue of Bahall, and settles in for a bad nights rest before descending deeper into the caves…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 27: Old Castien]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-27-Old-Castien</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-27-Old-Castien"/>
        <updated>2019-04-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Varyk, awaking alone on the shore of the Beast Coast, makes his way north and finds the wreck of ‘The Considered Response to Inquiry.’ Noticing it behaving strangely, he is able to commune with it, teleporting himself to an ascended version of the ship on a still seam, covered in dead elves. Realising the ship can be salvaged, he goes out in search of his party. Spying a ruin above that seems to exist in both ascension and the material plane, he finds his way into an ancient cliff-side fortress, half eroded into the sea. Here he finds the corpse of an ancient wizard, and takes his Fly Boots. Meeting up with a party of orcs, he makes his way along the same pilgrimage they had undertaken, catching up with Kharl and Dakarai just as Urllex disappears into Orthac’s Jawbone.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Varyk, awaking alone on the shore of the Beast Coast, makes his way north and finds the wreck of ‘The Considered Response to Inquiry.’ Noticing it behaving strangely, he is able to commune with it, teleporting himself to an ascended version of the ship on a still seam, covered in dead elves. Realising the ship can be salvaged, he goes out in search of his party. Spying a ruin above that seems to exist in both ascension and the material plane, he finds his way into an ancient cliff-side fortress, half eroded into the sea. Here he finds the corpse of an ancient wizard, and takes his Fly Boots. Meeting up with a party of orcs, he makes his way along the same pilgrimage they had undertaken, catching up with Kharl and Dakarai just as Urllex disappears into Orthac’s Jawbone.</p><p>The night before, Dakarai dreams of of Naivara talking with the drow that have been hunting the party. Though they speak in elvish, Dakarai identifies the words ‘Seshelas’ and ‘Gundren.’ Hoping to find Naivara before it is too late, Kharl, Dakarai and Varyk decide to travel light, leaving their allies and pets at Ittur and flying across the estuary to Castien. They are slowed when they realise they have to fly around a flock of feasting harpies, and arrive at the city as night falls. Flying close to the palace walls, they are engaged by a group of Alu-Tel scouts, and escape using sorcery to conjure storms and darkness to mask their retreat.</p><p>Separated as they arrive in the city, Kharl and Varyk befriend a group of Kenku playing chaospheres on a rooftop. The Kenku seem to have some fleeting relationship with Halia Thornton, as Kharl’s keen ear picks up from their speech. They also inform Kharl that there are ways into the palace through caves beneath the cliffs.</p><p>Experiencing the effects of the sand-curse, Dakarai finds himself at the Palace of Tears, before finding his way to the port district, narrowly dodging a group of familiar dwarfs near a safely docked ‘Heft and Consideration.’ Dakarai finds his way to a bar, where he befriends a 4-foot tall saurial paladin known as ‘Dragonbait.’ Drinking late into the night, Dragonbait and Dakarai run straight into the dwarfs from before, and go their separate ways as Varyk creates a wall of fire as a distraction. As they settle into an attic hideaway in the manor district, Dakarai dreams, not of the Palace of Tears, but of a dank and ancient crumbling stone building, and is set upon by insects, before waking.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 26: The Beast Coast]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-26-The-Beast-Coast</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-26-The-Beast-Coast"/>
        <updated>2019-03-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Crashing into the Beast Coast, the party becomes separated, with Lorna, Varyk and Dakarai thrown overboard. Kharl and Urllex abandon ship, gathering their soaked belongings on the white sand. Down the beach, they find Dakarai, who has lost his equipment in the process of being washed ashore, with no memory of washing up except for strange visions of sand.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Crashing into the Beast Coast, the party becomes separated, with Lorna, Varyk and Dakarai thrown overboard. Kharl and Urllex abandon ship, gathering their soaked belongings on the white sand. Down the beach, they find Dakarai, who has lost his equipment in the process of being washed ashore, with no memory of washing up except for strange visions of sand.</p><p>The party makes their way north towards Castien, stumbling upon the lair of a cave-dwelling psychic monstrosity (a Balhannoth) along the way, that almost devours the party, before finding a way up to the top of the shear cliffs with the help of Urllexin’s knowledge of the surroundings. Huddled in camp at the top of the cliffs, it becomes apparent in the night that something has happened to Dakarai, as he has visions in the night of the Palace of Tears in Castien.</p><p>The next day, the party comes across a war party of orcs, led by Arha Orthaci-Ittur, a childhood fried of Urllex. The party is taken on a pilgrimage through the orc settlements of Mur and Ittur, on the way to Urzoth’s old home at Orthac’s Jawbone. Over this time it becomes clear that Dakarai is merely a fragment of himself, and that his true body has been possessed by Naivara, who has escaped for some reason to the Palace of Tears.</p><p>Making their way down the cliffs towards Orthac’s Jawbone, the party finds themselves close to ascension, and Urllexin knows that she must continue alone…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 25: Heart of the Island]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-25-Heart-of-the-Island</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-25-Heart-of-the-Island"/>
        <updated>2019-02-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Making their way into the statue, which Kharl identifies as the diety Zemmutan, the party evades several challenges and traps to fulfill the Ritual of Dragon Ascension to receive a blessing in the form of a potion. Returning to the abandoned camp, the party identifies the signs that this might be a hastily abandoned White Iron Company outpost, destroyed by undead.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Making their way into the statue, which Kharl identifies as the diety Zemmutan, the party evades several challenges and traps to fulfill the Ritual of Dragon Ascension to receive a blessing in the form of a potion. Returning to the abandoned camp, the party identifies the signs that this might be a hastily abandoned White Iron Company outpost, destroyed by undead.</p><p>Travelling further into the island, the party finds a desecrated forest, above which floats <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/The Island Heart/new">The Island Heart</a>. With the help of Varyk’s new powers, the party is able to fly up to the island to explore it, finding signs it has been occupied by Edea Wormwood of the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/wormwood-fife-and-vanderbourne-independent-artificers">Independent Artificers Guild</a>.</p><p>They find a number of scrolls, as well as an imprisoned human woman, Liwei Brune, who they free and take with them as part of their crew. The party destroys Edea Wormwood’s teleportation circle, preventing her from returning to her lair.</p><p>On the return journey, Dakarai leads the party astray on the way home, and they stumble upon an undead Tyrannosaurus, which they are able to kill without taking almost any damage. Though severely damaged, the undead monster still returns to unlife after the party leaves.</p><p>Back out at sea, after another 10 days of travel, the ship runs into a storm, and though the crew try their best, they are unable to prevent the ship being driven away from the safe harbour and into the hostile southern Beast Coast…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 24: Eat, Pray, Love]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-24-Eat,-Pray,-Love</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-24-Eat,-Pray,-Love"/>
        <updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rivaan Kathvishargolin prepares to board the Heft and Consideration as Lorna and Urllex hide themselves to avoid being caught, surmising he is here for the Bracers. Kharl greets Rivaan, who accuses Captain Vondal of harbouring stowaways. As the conversation grows more heated, Urllex sneaks aboard the Eat, Pray, Love as a crab and attaches a feather token to the mast of the ship to prevent it from moving for 24 hours.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Rivaan Kathvishargolin prepares to board the Heft and Consideration as Lorna and Urllex hide themselves to avoid being caught, surmising he is here for the Bracers. Kharl greets Rivaan, who accuses Captain Vondal of harbouring stowaways. As the conversation grows more heated, Urllex sneaks aboard the Eat, Pray, Love as a crab and attaches a feather token to the mast of the ship to prevent it from moving for 24 hours.</p><p>As Rivaan begins to board the Heft and Consideration, Dakarai intervenes with a distraction, attempting to pull a small item out of his Cloak of Many Things. Instead, he pulls out an ancient Elven Galleon, which crushes half of those present, instantly killing Captain Vondal as well as the imprisoned accomplices of Lorna and Urllex from Perranalla.</p><p>The party engages in a heated melee with the crew of the Eat, Pray, Love, including a powerful air elemental summoned to speed up the ships journey. Kharl, stripped of his powers briefly by a spell cast by his cousin, is thrown overboard by the elemental and almost drowns, but is rescued by Urllex. Rivaan is crushed into the side of the Heft and Consideration by his own rogue elemental and is killed.</p><p>With Rivaan’s crew killed and the captain of the Heft and Consideration killed, the party takes control of the ship, press-ganging the uncooperative dwarves. In a fit of rage, Urllex kills one of the dwarves after they make a racist comment. To prevent further bloodshed, a small group of dwarves agree to help the party crew the elven galleon, identified as the lost royal longship The Considered Response to Inquiry.</p><p>Going their separate ways, the party spends a terse week at sea, before spotting <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/Isle Zemmutan/new">Isle Zemmutan</a> on the horizon and approaching it to explore and pick up supplies. Looking for another canoe, Dakarai starts emptying his robe of items, revealing, among other things, two trained mastiffs that he names “Grog” and “Grog.”</p><p>Landing at an abandoned camp, the party makes their way towards a giant dragon statue carved into the side of a cliff…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 23: The Mirror]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-23-The-Mirror</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-23-The-Mirror"/>
        <updated>2018-12-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Moving along the route determined by the scrying ceremony, the party makes it’s way out to sea, and gets to know the crew of the ‘Heft and Consideration.’ After a few days at sea, the party spies a signal flare sent out by a stranded ship. Dakarai approaches the ship, crashed against huge rocks, and sees a dwarf dragged below deck by a dark shape, returning to warn the party. The party is asked by Captain Vondal Ungart to board the vessel and discover what has happened.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Moving along the route determined by the scrying ceremony, the party makes it’s way out to sea, and gets to know the crew of the ‘Heft and Consideration.’ After a few days at sea, the party spies a signal flare sent out by a stranded ship. Dakarai approaches the ship, crashed against huge rocks, and sees a dwarf dragged below deck by a dark shape, returning to warn the party. The party is asked by Captain Vondal Ungart to board the vessel and discover what has happened.</p><p>Boarding the vessel and descending into the hold of the ship, the party finds the crew slaughtered. In the lowest level of the hold, knee deep in feted water, the party spies a mirror in the distance. They are quickly ambushed by demonic goat creatures that kidnap Varyk and drag him to the surface, with Lorna in pursuit. In the hold, the party engage the demons in combat. Kharl approaches the mirror and is enraptured by it, forced to attack his own party. The same charm falls upon Dakarai, and they engage each other in combat. Urllex kills the final demons with a thunderwave, knocking the mirror into the water and breaking the spell.</p><p>Meanwhile, Varyk is dragged before a lone tree at the top of the rocks, revealed to be full of worms. Kyuss speaks to Varyk, giving him an offer – Kyuss will call off his demons, if Varyk helps him find the entity that has split Kyuss into two beings, one a mindless vulture, the other an immaculate salesman. Varyk agrees, and Kyuss disappears.</p><p>Due to Urllex’s thunderwave, the ship turns on its side and begins to sink. The party escapes, but Kharl stays behind to cleanse the ship and recover the captain’s logbook. He sinks with the ship, but casts waterwalk on himself and pulls himself up from the depths.</p><p>The party returns to the ship and Kharl confronts Captain Vondal, accusing him of cowardice, leaving the crew feeling conflicted about the groups presence. A shaky peace follows for the next few days of travel, when Kharl spots from the back of the ship something he didn’t expect to see – the ‘Eat, Pray, Love,’ appraching at speed, captained by Kharl’s cousin, Rivaan Kathvishargolin…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 22: Setting Sail]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-22-Setting-Sail</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-22-Setting-Sail"/>
        <updated>2018-11-25T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party decides to go on to Perranala, the capital city of the Dragon Isles, and from there try and get a boat to travel to the Beast Coast without risking going straight through the Lodestone network. Stepping through, they find themselves in a crowded, hot bazaar, a climate only a few of them have experienced before.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party decides to go on to Perranala, the capital city of the Dragon Isles, and from there try and get a boat to travel to the Beast Coast without risking going straight through the Lodestone network. Stepping through, they find themselves in a crowded, hot bazaar, a climate only a few of them have experienced before.</p><p>Kharl goes looking for a ship, while Urllex looks for a criminal contact to get access to a bow. Lorna and Dakarai spend some time spending coin and drinking with nobles, befriending the affluent Dwarfish noble, Ushar Ungart.</p><p>Kharl, dejected by how commerce-driven the city has become, finds his way to the Temple of Sunne, where he is revered for his knowledge of the outside world, and is offered a place on a ship going on a pilgrimage out to the outer islands. Urllex finds his contact in Malar’s Throat, a rundown part of the city, and is told of a shipment coming in to town the next evening on the merchant vessel Eat, Pray, Love.</p><p>The party gathers in the grand bazaar to continue drinking, and Ushar offers to put everyone up in her manor for the evening, and gives them a job working security on a ship going to the Beast Coast in two days time. Urllex fills Lorna in on the plan, but keeps the others out of it.</p><p>The next morning, Dakarai hunts down the ship and makes introductions – slightly too drunk, and doesn’t make the best impression.</p><p>Kharl spends the day getting ready for the journey – using up his last favour with the Church of Tymora to ensure Horsetina and Justice find their way back to Espis and loading all their gear onto the ship. Afterwards, he makes his way into the poorer parts of the city, and is happy to see the old ways being practiced.</p><p>Lorna and Urllex find a good ambush spot to steal the shipment, and hunt down some accomplices to act as muscle for the job that evening. The four that they hire, three dragonborn and a tiefling, none of them speaking a word of common, agree to meet them that evening. With Lorna up in the rooftops watching carefully, the heist goes off without a hitch, and the group are able to disappear into the night with a chest of gold and Urllex’s prize: rare, enchanted Bracers of Archery.</p><p>The next morning, the ship sets sail, out of Perranala harbour and into the chaos of the Outer Reaches. To ready themselves for the journey, Kharl performs a chaosphere scrying ceremony, and with this as a guide, the party divines their path forward..</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 21: The Sand Curse]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-21-The-Sand-Curse</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-21-The-Sand-Curse"/>
        <updated>2018-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party has on a brief period to explore the inside of the pyramid, floating at the center of which is a giant sphere of sand, before the spirit of Naivara Belanor appears and banishes Varyk and Lorna with a tidal wave of sand.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party has on a brief period to explore the inside of the pyramid, floating at the center of which is a giant sphere of sand, before the spirit of Naivara Belanor appears and banishes Varyk and Lorna with a tidal wave of sand.</p><p>The party is immediately drawn into combat, with Urllex successfully pulling the brunt of the attacks towards herself, almost killed by a cone of cold. After a few rounds of dicey combat, the party emerges on top as Dakarai uses all of his ki to stun the archmage, again and again, before she is overwhelmed. The archmage dismissed for now, Kharl repairs the damage to the magical tablets within the pyramid, forcing the sphere of sand back into it’s prison and allowing Varyk and Lorna to return.</p><p>Curious, Dakarai approaches the sphere, and inadvertently takes the Curse of Sand into his amulet. The curse trapped once again, the door to the room opens and the party step out to discover they are in Lillen Shadowcloak’s office. The party briefly looks around, finding nothing they can understand, and while the rest of the party goes ahead, Kharl starts a fire, burning away all evidence of the curse, and Lillen’s writings.</p><p>Making their way through Highhaven, the party discover that the rebellion has succeeded, and the old order has been overthrown. They say their goodbyes to Pog and Chaddeus, before retrieving Justice and Horsetina (after walking headfirst, once again, into the invisible statue of Magicami). Leaving the university, they discover the city marked with plenty of signs of combat, and a shrine to Leto Halfhand, who evidently died fighting the Witchhunters sent by the Inner Ring.</p><p>The party makes their way to the Highhaven Lodestone, where the guards inform them that they are free to go anywhere they want, but once they leave, they cannot come back. The party pauses to consider what the next move might be…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 20: The Crystal Spire]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-20-The-Crystal-Spire</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-20-The-Crystal-Spire"/>
        <updated>2018-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a cold night sheltered in the snow, the party makes their way towards the Crystal Spire, all the while followed from above by an unknown druid and stalked at a distance by an invisible demon. Progress is slow – the party is not used to arctic conditions and loses time getting turned around. After another night in the snow, the group finds their way to the entry of the Spire, guarded by the bored fox demon Yrkhetep, who, due to a lack of visitors, has turned the entrance to the Spire into a tropical sculpture garden, dedicated to his foxy visage.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a cold night sheltered in the snow, the party makes their way towards the Crystal Spire, all the while followed from above by an unknown druid and stalked at a distance by an invisible demon. Progress is slow – the party is not used to arctic conditions and loses time getting turned around. After another night in the snow, the group finds their way to the entry of the Spire, guarded by the bored fox demon <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/yrkhetep">Yrkhetep</a>, who, due to a lack of visitors, has turned the entrance to the Spire into a tropical sculpture garden, dedicated to his foxy visage.</p><p>Presenting the demon with the three seals of Highhaven, the party is allowed into the main scrying room of the complex. After examining the machinery and praying on it’s use, Dakarai, Varyk and Kharl are able to piece together how to open the portal to Ascension, where they enter into Lillen’s domain, causing the fractal palace to immediately become unstable.</p><p>Fleeing into the fractal palace, the party finds themselves in a recursive, endless library, filled with more of Lillen’s notes. By piecing these notes together with those Varyk had already collected, they are able to fully decode her notes, revealing a piece of her history that allows them further into the maze. Each layer of the maze seems to be a thousand fractal pathways, linked with Lillen or one of her companions, with the true entrance hidden among hundreds of near copies.</p><p>Through, the home of Urzoth, aunt of Urllex, followed by the temple of Rhobsarendor for Kharl’s grandfather, and the Gnarl for the druid Kaz, the party sees glimpses of the parties history, a group pulled together by natural forces in opposition to a dark force growing in the Deep.</p><p>While exploring, the party begins to become aware that they are not alone – thousands of fragments of Naivara can be seen trying endless doors around them, the wizard resorting to brute force to beat the party to their prize.</p><p>The party then finds themselves deep within Kyuss’ lair, and discover the treasure that the old party sought – seven vials, almost entirely lacking in ornament, each filled with a different liquid. The shade of Gundren asks Lillen why there are seven vials, as they were only sent to retrieve six. Lillen replies to leave the seventh, not even to look at it. The party takes six, leaving the last, pure black, alone in it’s recess.</p><p>The last vision the party is left with is with Tock, the partys rogue, going his own way, the adventure finished, one of the vials in a circlet around his neck. The vial seems to have given Tock the ability to misty step at will. Lillen cautions him to take his curse seriously, as it will overcome him if he isn’t careful, but Tock remains jovial. The party is able to deduce that from their last encounter with the Drow, where the could now misty step, that Tock has been killed, and his power somehow absorbed by his attackers.</p><p>With the last layer of the maze completed, the party finds themselves in a final, pyramidal structure, at the center of which is their prize – an empty vial, floating in space, surrounded by a floating orb of sand…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 19: Solitude]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-19-Solitude</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-19-Solitude"/>
        <updated>2018-07-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party gathers their things and makes their way out of the university proper into Highhaven itself, with the goal of finding Jasper Goodbarrel who would help them on their way to the Crystal Spire.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party gathers their things and makes their way out of the university proper into Highhaven itself, with the goal of finding Jasper Goodbarrel who would help them on their way to the Crystal Spire.</p><p>While the party stopped for a well-earned drink at the local dive the Wizard Have Tavern (loosely translated from the abyssal “Wizards have nothing to fear from this, an ordinary tavern”). There they met Debope the Wheel’d, a magicless Beholder who tended bar using his eyestalks.</p><p>While the party relaxed, Kharl made his way to the local Church of Tymora party, making their way out of the city after their failed quest to retrieve Bojangles spellbook at the university, and convinced them to stay and protect the citizens in the inevitable battle for Highhaven.</p><p>Getting directions to Jasper’s establishment, the Woof &amp; Whistle Inn, the party meets the halfling and are kitted out with a guide and supplies to make a journey out onto the ice. Kharl gets the sense that he is being watched, but can’t quite follow who or why.</p><p>Leaving the city by sleds led by fey Borzois, the party slowly gets the sense that their guide is not telling them the full truth when he recommends they stop early and shelter, rather than make their way straight to the spire. Sure enough, he betrays them, dismissing the summoned sled dogs and making a break for it in the snow, though he is swiftly recaptured by Varyk and Dakarai. Shortly after, the party is attacked by a group of mercenaries led by two Drow, exhibiting the same characteristics as the doppelganger of the Black Spider.</p><p>In the melee, a fireball is thrown at the sleds and supplies, incinerating them. While a few of the group go down, the tide is turned as the mercenaries begin to scatter, attacked by an unknown adversary in the snow that none of the party can see.</p><p>Towards the end of the fight, the last Drow demonstrates a new ability when she misty steps from the ground directly into Urllex’s grasp, and tells her that “they found her friend” and that they have taken her power for themselves, before being skewered by a javelin thrown by Varyk.</p><p>With the melee over, the party stops to nurse their wounds, sheltering in a portable hole pulled from Dakarai’s Cloak of Many Things, in the middle of nowhere, as night approaches…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 18: Tensions, Confrontations, Rebellion]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-18-Tensions,-Confrontations,-Rebellion</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-18-Tensions,-Confrontations,-Rebellion"/>
        <updated>2018-06-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party visits Gamble Silverthread in his office in order to retrieve his promised House of Stars Seal for delivering him Bojangles spellbook. He thanks the party and offers them a reward of a potion, a scroll, and a vape rig. While he is briefly distracted by a spell going off outside his window, Lorna pinches a letter that caught her eye – an invitation from the Independent Artificers Guild to the Wizard of Wines Winery in the Portal City of Castien, a month from now. As they are leaving Silverthreads office, one of his demons identifies Varyk as a man that Kyuss has been searching for.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party visits <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/prof-gamble-silverthread">Gamble Silverthread</a> in his office in order to retrieve his promised House of Stars Seal for delivering him Bojangles spellbook. He thanks the party and offers them a reward of a potion, a scroll, and a vape rig. While he is briefly distracted by a spell going off outside his window, Lorna pinches a letter that caught her eye – an invitation from <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/wormwood-fife-and-vanderbourne-independent-artificers">the Independent Artificers Guild</a> to the Wizard of Wines Winery in <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-portal-city-of-castien">the Portal City of Castien</a>, a month from now. As they are leaving Silverthreads office, one of his demons identifies Varyk as a man that Kyuss has been searching for.</p><p>In the first year dorms, tempers are high, and the students are starting to congregate along class lines. Chaddeus is attacked and beaten for not being a citizen of the Inner Ring. Tensions come to a head in that evenings vaping showdown, soundly won through the team effort of Dakarai and Lorna, when the Outer Ring students are ambushed by a force led by <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/reddlepop-pilwiken">Professor Pilwiken</a>, much to the horror of his son, Wrenn. Kharl and Urllexin break through the magical trap and confront Pilwiken, who retreats when Kharl forces him to cough up sand by weaponising his knowledge of the House of Cloaks.</p><p>The party leads the first years out of the trap through a secret entrance discovered by Varyk, and regroup in the sewers. Sickened by his fathers behavour, Wrenn gives the party the third and final seal they need. Kharl teaches the students to repeat the mantra about the fourth house without them trying to understand it, allowing them to weaponise it further to incapacitate those that would harm them. Pog leads the students to take first year dorm, driving out the Inner Ring students.</p><p>The attack on the first years leads to the expelling of a large amount of sand, with accretes into the form of Lillen Shadowcloak, hunting Naivara, who has reappeared, attracted by the fighting. As Lillen goes to strike, Varyk summons a magic circle around Lillen, trapping her sand form within, using up the last of his amulets protection magic in the process.</p><p>Trapped within the circle, Lillen reveals a portion of her plan to break a set of seals located deep within her fortress, when Kharl unwittingly reveals to her a clue (a clue tied to Urllex’s past). Lillen asks the party what they know of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/deep-sashelas">Deep Sashelas</a>, and is intrigued when the party seems confused by this.Finally, Lillen reveals herself to be none other than a fragment of Naivara Belanor, much to the distress and confusion of the Naivara outside of the circle.</p><p>The evil Naivara dissapates, while the good Naivara asks the party to hurry to the Crystal Spire and find the essence of Sand within before she does. She tells the party to leave Highhaven and find Jasper Goodbarrel, who would lead them to where they need to go.</p><p>The party, realising that they need to confront Leto in order to leave via the main gate, asks Pog to gather Ravencrow and Kirk. Khark calls Leto out, and after a few minutes of frantic shouting, Leto emerges, shrouded in magical energy. Kirk and Ravencrow appear, flanked by a suprising asset – the thirty three mages that gave Kirk her nickname, freed and ready to take part in open rebellion.</p><p>Outnumbered, and knowing that any conflict would lead to the Inner Ring cleansing the entire school anyway, Leto chooses to help the rebellion and begins making for the Lodestone to head off the inevitable Inner Ring reinforcements.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 17: The Meat Centrifuge of Kathud-Ra]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-17-The-Meat-Centrifuge-of-Kathud-Ra</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-17-The-Meat-Centrifuge-of-Kathud-Ra"/>
        <updated>2018-05-13T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a brief rest, the party identifies that the room they are in contains a magical ward designed to repel abhorrent creatures. Urllex surmises that this is similar to the work of Dumica Kirk. Moving deeper into the cave, the party finally discovers the source of the homunculus plague – an imprisoned chunk of Doug, taken from the fleshwaste. The seal surrounding the creature had been pierced by the inquisitive student, and his body used as a way to begin Doug’s escape.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a brief rest, the party identifies that the room they are in contains a magical ward designed to repel abhorrent creatures. Urllex surmises that this is similar to the work of Dumica Kirk. Moving deeper into the cave, the party finally discovers the source of the homunculus plague – <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-fleshwaste">an imprisoned chunk of Doug, taken from the fleshwaste.</a> The seal surrounding the creature had been pierced by the inquisitive student, and his body used as a way to begin Doug’s escape.</p><p>The party goes about the process of cutting away at the web of flesh extending out from the weasley husk, as the very walls of the cave start coming detaching and attacking the party. After a few well timed blasts of thunder by Urllex, Kharl runs forward and severs the connection between Doug and the boys husk, destroying the remaining monstrosities and resealing the prison.</p><p>While Doug continuously whispers to be freed, the party retreats beyond his sphere of influence with the boys husk in tow. Professor Ravencrow emerges from the cave entrance, overjoyed that she was 100% not responsible for any of this and that there wasn’t any need for an investigation. She also identifies the prison as Professor Kirks handiwork, and is bewildered by this turn of events.</p><p>Kirk appears, and reveals that she was keeping the creature a secret as part of a birthday surprise, a newly reassembled Meat Centrifuge of Kathud-Ra. Professor Ravencrow is overjoyed, and leaps into Kirks arms, thanking the party for repairing her broken marriage. Kirk responds with “we were fine.”</p><p>Taking the party in to the centrifuge, they find that although it is in need of repair, the mincer attached to it is working fine. They mince the weasley boys corpse, freeing his soul, which Crows traps in a jar. She then injects the newly freed soul into one of the remaining homunculi, as this would be cheaper than a proper resurrection, but after a moment of sentience and clarity the homunculus immediately throws itself straight back into the mincer. Crows agrees to pay for a proper resurrection, and hands over the seal of the House of Coins.</p><p>Setting serious, Kirk thanks Kharl for bringing her to her senses. Tells Crows that something bad is going on, has been going on for a while, and they might need to “accelerate their plan,” as Half-hand is turning against the faculty, but that there is still time to turn him to their cause, as he wears a slave mark, the same as them.</p><p>Impatient to keep adventuring, Kharl leaves, getting hopelessly lost in the sewers.</p><p>Kirk instructs the rest of the party to carry on with their plan and gather the remaining seals required to access the crystal spire. Ravencrow snaps her fingers, transmuting everyone else’s robes into prefect robes, giving them free reign of school.</p><p>The party returns to the dorms, collapsing in bed without telling anyone in the gathered throng of first years where the were. Kharl stumbles back after an epiphany in the sewers that he can’t rely on his god to always protect him, and that he needs to learn to be a martial fighter.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 16: The Weasley Child]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-16-The-Weasley-Child</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-16-The-Weasley-Child"/>
        <updated>2018-04-08T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party wakes to find the university on lockdown, and rumors that Halfhand is turning over the school hunting for a group that attacked him in the night.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party wakes to find the university on lockdown, and rumors that Halfhand is turning over the school hunting for a group that attacked him in the night.</p><p>Kharl gives himself up, intending to confront Halfhand, but is intercepted and the party is taken before Professor Kirk. She instructs the party to keep a low profile. Kharl confronts her about the hidden School of Cloaks, leading to Kirk vomiting sand and forcibly expelling Kharl from the room.</p><p>The party skirts across the banned central courtyard to the main university building, intending to hand over Bojangles spellbook to Gamble Silverthread. They get sidetracked when they find him with Professor Ravencrow in the basement, dealing with an overflowing mess of weasley looking children.</p><p>Denying all knowledge of why this would be happening, Ravencrow sends the party into the sewers once again, to finally discover the source of the creatures. In the sewers, the party follows a trail of homonculi to the source, a burst pipe leading into an ancient part of the school.</p><p>Fighting their way through a sea of mutant schoolboys, the party makes their way into the mutants sanctum.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 15: Portal Shenanigans]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-15-Portal-Shenanigans</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-15-Portal-Shenanigans"/>
        <updated>2018-03-11T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having all successfully made it into the hidden library, the party begins to explore the first chambers, finding finding tomes in various languages. Amongst the pages, Varyk finds a bunch of loose pages of a journal written in some kind of cypher, in an increasingly distressed hand.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having all successfully made it into the hidden library, the party begins to explore the first chambers, finding finding tomes in various languages. Amongst the pages, Varyk finds a bunch of loose pages of a journal written in some kind of cypher, in an increasingly distressed hand.  </p><p> Experimenting with a lever in the room, they discover that what appeared to be doors are actually portals to different spaces.</p><p>Kharl goes into a portal, emerging into a tower far above an ashen landscape. There he finds an ancient pedestal, with a gem atop it. He discovers that manipulating this gem causes changes within the library. Using this pedestal, he opens two further portals to a beautiful clearing and a tiered amphitheatre in  <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-valley-of-tombs">the Valley of Tombs</a>.</p><p>In that room, Urllex examines a series of mirrors, that seem to reflect images of death or looming danger. While this is happening, Lorna spies something through another portal – her bow, held by a mephit. She leaps through, and is cut off from the rest of the group when the mephit succeeds in knocking a chunk of stone off the pedestal. Urllex panics, as this reminds her of the time she lost her friend Jimmy in another wizards tower. They set off to search for Lorna, further into the dungeon.</p><p>The party makes their way through the portals, activating pedestals to open and close portals as they go, eventually finding the way to Bojangles spellbook, and an interaction with Lillen Shadowcloak, who goads them through a mirror until Kharl shatters it, revealling a torrent of sand behind.</p><p>Determining that there is a single room they haven’t been able to access, Kharl leads the party back through the library, activating and deactivating portals until finally, they activate a route through to a final room, which has a inactive pedestal similar to the one Lorna ran through. After some trial and error, Varyk learns from Bojangles tome that the portal can be accessed by placing an object from the place you wish to access into the pedestal. They pour sand onto the pedestal, and are immediately faced with a new sight – a sand blasted desert ruin, covered in items stolen from the party and from other students, swarming with demonic mephits.</p><p>Running to a cornered Lorna’s aid, the party gathers thier gear and fights back against the creatures. Victorious, they stop to take stock of the environment – a desert outcrop in ascension, watched over with an endless, fractal fortress – Lillen’s lair. Reactivating the portal to lead back to the University dormatory, the party stumbled back to bed.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 14: The Three Seals]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-14-The-Three-Seals</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-14-The-Three-Seals"/>
        <updated>2018-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Visiting Bloodcrow Ravencrow, Kharl and Lorna learn that the student she refers to as ‘the weasley looking boy’ was entrusted with a powerful resurrection amulet on the account of his family being rich and students dying all the time. Apparently the amulet has backfired somehow, and humunculus copies of the boy have been appearing in the sewers ever since. Ravencrow attempts to wipe the parties memories, but is unable to as a powerful spell has already been cast on them. Deciding instead to work with the group, Ravencrow promises the use of the House of Coins Seal as payment for quietly dealing with ‘the weasley problem.’ Leaving the office, Kharl is accosted by Wimple Womble (no relation), who tells him to stay away from the sewer and not to nark to the faculty about what is happening down there.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Visiting Bloodcrow Ravencrow, Kharl and Lorna learn that the student she refers to as ‘the weasley looking boy’ was entrusted with a powerful resurrection amulet on the account of his family being rich and students dying all the time. Apparently the amulet has backfired somehow, and humunculus copies of the boy have been appearing in the sewers ever since. Ravencrow attempts to wipe the parties memories, but is unable to as a powerful spell has already been cast on them. Deciding instead to work with the group, Ravencrow promises the use of the House of Coins Seal as payment for quietly dealing with ‘the weasley problem.’ Leaving the office, Kharl is accosted by Wimple Womble (no relation), who tells him to stay away from the sewer and not to nark to the faculty about what is happening down there.</p><p>While this is happening, Varyk, Dakarai and Urllex go to confront Leto Halfhand about his strange behaviour – blanking Varyk completely and ignoring the party in general – in the past week. Upon being cornered, Leto is unable to deal with the existence of the party, vomiting sand uncontroliably and crying out for them to leave. The group engages Halfhand in combat, but before any damage can be done, a swarm of mephits cohalese out of the sand and decend on the party. They wake up, remembering very little, except for Urllex, who vividly remembers the event and re-explains it to the group, hypothesising that something is being done to them that is affecting their memories.</p><p>Putting this aside for the meantime, the party splits up, with Urllex going to class to attempt to get some answers out of the divination teacher, while the rest of the party goes into the sewer to look for the weasley boy. Finding their way deep into the sewers, the party stumbles upon Wimple Wombles humunculus fighting arena, where he has been secretly forcing the weasley boys to fight at night. Taking his prize weasley, the party uses him to find thier way down to the source, a vast copper boiler that seems to be producing the homunculi at a steady rate. Blocking the boiler exhaust, the party returns to the surface to wait for the weasleys to start emerging elsewhere.</p><p>Urllex stops in her search for a teacher when she notices tracks in the snow – sandy tracks. Chasing down her prey, she discovers the creature she has been hunting is an elven woman who recognises Urllex and calls her by name before passing out. Taking her back to the dorm, the party exchanges stories and waits for her to regain consciousness.</p><p>The elf reveals herself to be Naivara Belanor, member of the House of Cloaks, a house that originally ran the school but has been secreted away by Lillen Shadowcloak’s powerful magic. The party remembers now – a few weeks ago, they made an attempt on Lillen’s fortress, but they were ambushed by mephits and overwhelmed. Thus began their brainwashed careers as first year wizards in training.</p><p>Naivara raises another option – accessing Lillen’s realm using the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-crystal-spire">the Crystal Spire</a>, which is currently locked and can only be accessed by receiving three seals, one from each House.</p><p>With a new sense of purpose, the party approaches Gamble Silverthread of the House of Lights, who hints that there is a demon haunting the library at present who may or may not be there as an imposition to a group of inquistitors from the church of Tymora, who have heard that the library contains the spellbook of Bojangles. He mentions that retrieving the book, which has caused so many issues, would indeed be worthy of a seal.</p><p>Leaving Silverthreads office, the party bangs again runs into local bully Wimple Womble (no relation). Wimple is furious that the party has disrupted their underground humunculus fighting ring, and demands that Lorna face him in a final vape-off to decide who rules the school.</p><p>Leaving this for now, the party sneaks into the forbidden part of the library – a nightmare maze without logic or gravity –  and leaps through traps while avoiding the fists of a large, angry demon. Locating the place where the heard, weeks ago, Bojangles spellbook was stored, the party activates a secret door, revealing a hidden, mazelike dungeon beyond…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 13: I Love Wizard School]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-13-I-Love-Wizard-School</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-13-I-Love-Wizard-School"/>
        <updated>2017-12-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party wakes up, excited for their first day at wizard school. Only a few of them have memories indicating that anything might be amiss. Walking to orientation, the party is introduced to a number of fellow magic students, including their roommate Pog Oomtrowel, resident jock Chaddeus Gimlen, and the dragonborn noble Greethen Firahel.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party wakes up, excited for their first day at wizard school. Only a few of them have memories indicating that anything might be amiss. Walking to orientation, the party is introduced to a number of fellow magic students, including their roommate Pog Oomtrowel, resident jock Chaddeus Gimlen, and the dragonborn noble Greethen Firahel.</p><p>Over the course of the first week, the party begins to realise that something is very wrong – they are obviously ill equiped to be attending wizard school, and thinking certain thoughts leads to the coughing up of gritty sand – the same sand that Urllexin has been tracking around the school, unable to locate the source. Skipping class to investigate the school, Dakarai stumbles upon a note that seems to have fallen out of his own robes;</p><p><em>“Wait until dark. Meet S.R. Wear the clothes he gives you. Meet under Glain at midnight. We prepare and make for L.”</em></p><p>After the first week of school, the party has barely learned any spells, and their inconsistent behaviour is starting to worry Pog, who doesn’t want to be lumped in with ‘the bad kids.’ On the first day of rest since school started, the group attends an underground vape party in the sewers below the first year dormitories, where Kharl engineers events so that Pog is able to prove himself as a party animal and cement himself within the student culture.</p><p>Deciding to see if the sewers connect to the library through the sewers for some midnight studying, Kharl and Dakarai leave the party and set out on their own. In a long stretch of sewer tunnel, they run into a strange sight – a young student wandering by himself. The boy looks up and mutters a single word: “scabbers!”</p><p>After this strange event, the pair reach the library and are promptly caught and kicked out by the librarian, Silent Randy – potentially the mysterious “S.R” mentioned in the note Dakarai found.</p><p>The week continues on as normal, with Dakarai missing the most classes, much to the irritation of his bunkmate Pog. Skipping class once again, Dakarai confronts Silent Randy with the note later that week, and Randy reveals a set of visitors robes that had been in his office – the robes that the party were wearing when the first arrived at the school. Independently, Urllexin leaves the dorms at nights, and identifies the ‘Glain’ from the note – an ancient carving of one of Highhavens founders. Unfortunately, she walks directly into the statue of Magicami, and is forced to run back to bed without investigating further.</p><p>After one particular class with the necromancer Bloodcrow Ravencrow, the teacher casually asks the students that any information relating to the wherabouts of a ‘weasley looking boy’ wandering in the sewers should be reported directly to her, in her office…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 12: To Solitude]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-12-To-Solitude</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-12-To-Solitude"/>
        <updated>2017-12-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the weeks after Gundren’s death, the party drifts apart. Varyk, after being briefly detained, flees to the woods, and attempts to learn more about his possession and the amulet that seems to be holding it at bay. Lorna resumes a life of living off the land, dwelling on the outskirts of Phandalin.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the weeks after Gundren’s death, the party drifts apart. Varyk, after being briefly detained, flees to the woods, and attempts to learn more about his possession and the amulet that seems to be holding it at bay. Lorna resumes a life of living off the land, dwelling on the outskirts of Phandalin.</p><p>Urllex returns with Hudson to New Haven, working with the Crossroad Knights and shipping confiscated White Iron weapons back home to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-beast-coast">the Beast Coast</a>.</p><p>Kharl, after a brief period of soul searching, spends time with Aust and Aelar, learning the ways of the ‘civilised’ religions. During this time, he gains favour with the church of Tymora.</p><p>The party is reunited when word spreads that the mysterious monk Dakarai, who has been comatose since the seige of the spellforge, has awoken. Dakarai, after a game of 7-sphere chaosphere chess with Eilyac, the current avatar of Death, has indeed awoken a changed man, and has taken to drinking heavily in The Sleeping Giant.</p><p>Reunited again, the party travels to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/arborox">Arborox</a> to deal with some unfinished business – the young green dragon that has made the town as its nest. The party develops a plan to stab the dragon with an improvised iron stake, and then defeat the creature by heating the metal magically. Sneaking up to the tower, Dakarai accidently wakes the beast prematurely, and has to make a quick escape on his broomstick. The dragon goes to give chase, but is distracted by Kharl, taunting the creature from the middle of the road.</p><p>The dragon dives for Kharl, and the party uses the opportunity to pile on – the dragons hide is pierced and damage is piled on, while illusions of party members emerging out of the woods confuse it. Very quickly the creature is overpowered and killed.</p><p>Returning to Phandalin, the party hears news that Hudson is looking to escort Iarno Alberk back to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-portal-city-of-highhaven">Highhaven University</a> where he is to be tried as a deserter. Seeing this as an opportunity to visit the school and fulfil Gundren’s request to seek out the headmaster, the party sets out for <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-portal-city-of-new-haven">the Portal City of New Haven</a>, and after a leisurely few days shopping and drinking,  takes the wizard into their custody.</p><p>After escorting Iarno through the Lodestone portal into Solitude, the party makes for the university gates. The party is detained by Leto Halfhand, the elven spellsword in charge of defence and security. The party is escorted into the university (their weapons and magical items confiscated), and given visitors robes. Heading up the main path into the campus, Kharl walks straight into an invisible statue of the Wizard Magicami, left there in a last act of defiance before he escaped into Ascension.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 11: The Siege of the Spellforge]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-11-The-Siege-of-the-Spellforge</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-11-The-Siege-of-the-Spellforge"/>
        <updated>2017-11-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dakarai returns with news that additional troops will be coming from the White Iron camp. Weary from their last combat, the party decides to build up defences and make a stand within the Spellforge.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dakarai returns with news that additional troops will be coming from the White Iron camp. Weary from their last combat, the party decides to build up defences and make a stand within the Spellforge.</p><p>Dakarai floods the area in front of the spellforge by redirecting a river, creating a swampy muck suitable for the tiring bullywugs to hide. As the water rises, it floods the maze and entraceway of the mine, creating a perfect defensive line. The flooding is complete just in time, as the woods that the attackers were hiding in become wreathed in flame, presumably started by the White Iron troops in an attempt to drive the bulywugs back into the swamp.</p><p>Dakarai, Kharl and Hudson stay back to guard the mines, while the others make thier way along the cliffs through thick smoke. Spying the White Iron camp, they notice that they are mounting up for combat, while the rest of the camp packs up and heads for the hills. Kharl and Dakarai tend to the wounded, and Kharl returns Leventius’ Bane to Hudson, reinvigorating his morale.</p><p>Urllex leads the groups through the burning woods and extends the brushfire further onto the plain, forcing the approaching knights to dismount and make their way into the thick smoke along the cliff if they want to attack at all.</p><p>Returning to the Spellforge through the maze, the trio notice something amiss – the bodies of dead bullywugs floating in the waist-deep water. Immediately, the trio are set upon by a pair of Displacer Beasts – the monsters that destroyed Lorna’s home. A short, brutal fight plays out in the water, the party short on health and spells, the displacer beasts ripping and tearing with powerful tentacles. Dakarai goes down after recieving two powerful blows to the chest, and Kharl is flayed within an inch of his life. After the beasts are finally killed, the party returns to land to tend to the wounded, completely exhausted. Though Dakarai has been stabalised, he will not wake.</p><p>Back with the other defenders, they find that the bullywugs seem to have ambushed the last of the human attackers, sappers who had intended to bring the mine down on their heads. The party waits out the night, and no further attack comes. Emerging the next day, they find the White Iron company gone, obviously appalled at their own losses.</p><p>Time passes, and the party returns to Phandalin, where they spend weeks recuperating. Dakarai connot be roused, either by medicine or magic, and Kharl concludes that he is trapped in his coma by some powerful entity that he can see brief flashes of when he touches Dakarai’s mind.</p><p>Lorna and Urllex make contact with Halia Thornton, who is now the new mayor, and she suggests that if they want to stop the White Iron Company, they need to target the people paying them – a group of Artificers known as <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/wormwood-fife-and-vanderbourne-independent-artificers">Wormwood, Fife and Vanderbourne.</a></p><p>Kharl gets in a serious disagreement with Halia over her pardoning of two of the redbrand thugs he had arrested – dragging them by their necks most of the way to the gibbet before he is talked down. He spends the rest of the stay in Phandalin hiding away in the Leventius estate feeling sorry for himself.</p><p>The unexpected return of a large halfling contingent from New Haven leads to an impromptu celebration, and also the return of Gundren Rockseeker, who had been in New Haven trying to settle his affairs.</p><p>Taking the party aside for a meeting, Gundren crypically reveals to the party that decades ago, him, Urllexin’s aunt, and Kharls grandfather saved the world, and that now they are cursed, and refuses to explain how or what from, saying that it would put them all in danger.</p><p>Gundren has in his hands a set of amulets to prevent against scrying, and says they don’t know how much the drows saw when they used the scrying room within the Spellforge, and that they might not have much time.</p><p>He tells the party has his funds have been cut off due to civil war in the underdark, and that because of this he plans to organise an expedition to find out what is happening in the drow kingdoms. While he does this, he gives the party two tasks – to go to Highhaven University and contact the headmaster, and to travel to Skypiercer temple to help Kharl the Elder ascend as Rhobsarendor.</p><p>Kharl asks Gundren “what he knows of salt,” the curse that had befallen his grandfather. Suprisingly, this causes Kyuss, present within Varyk, to snarl in fury.</p><p>Seemingly putting two and two about something together, Kyuss fully possesses Varyk and assaults Gundren,  crying out in Abyssal, accusing him of theft. The party desperately tries to free Gundren, but Kyuss is too strong. Some quick thinking on Kharls part leads him to realise that Gundrens amulets would hopefully prevent demonic possession, and manages to get the necklace around Varyks neck.</p><p>While this successfully frees Varyk from Kyuss’s control (and banishes Kyuss from his mind), the damage has already been done – Gundren is dead.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 6.5: Isle Rhob]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-6.5-Isle-Rhob</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-6.5-Isle-Rhob"/>
        <updated>2017-07-24T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While staying the with the Bullywugs during the events of Chapter 6, the bullywug druid Kermshug leads Urllexin to a secluded saltwater lake, telling her that in the waters, people who need it can sometimes see a road into ascension. In the waters, Kharl sees the shadowy reflection of Isle Rhob, his grandfathers home and the old temple of his God.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While staying the with the Bullywugs during the events of Chapter 6, the bullywug druid Kermshug leads Urllexin to a secluded saltwater lake, telling her that in the waters, people who need it can sometimes see a road into ascension. In the waters, Kharl sees the shadowy reflection of Isle Rhob, his grandfathers home and the old temple of his God.</p><p>Urllex, transforming for the first time into a Manta Shark, leads the others into the water, and helps them cross over into ascension. They find themselves on a dark beach, the torches of the temple of Rhobsarendor burning high across the water from them.</p><p>The party searches for a boat, finding a hamlet stripped clean of materials. Urllexin tracks some clawprints back to a trible of kobolds living in the woods east of the hamlet. The kobolds revealed that they had only taken the goods after the hamlet was deserted, and revealed that the temple to the north had been overrun by “faceless giants.” Kharl says that they aim to destroy these faceless horrors, and the kobolds support their effort by offering powerful arrows and a shallow-hull boat.</p><p>Crossing the water, the party makes thier way up the cliffs towards the statue-garden that sits on the plateau below Rhobs temple. Lorna, sick of being soaking wet, takes the stairs, while Kharl sheds his armor and takes Urllex with him to scale the cliff from the ocean side. Kharl suprises and throws a faceless guardian off of the cliff, to be eaten by Urllex in shark-form. This brings the other guardians, faceless dragonborn acolytes, out of their stupor, and a melee begins. Urllex leaps her way up the cliff, vine-whipping one of the creatures off of the edge, while Kharl and Lorna engage them in melee combat, making short work of the acolytes, who crumble into salt, while another guardian is torn to shreds by vines summoned by Urllex. While they rest, and Kharl re-equips his armour, Lorna notes that all of the carvings on the various monuments are either written in gibberish or blank.</p><p>Climbing to the temple itself, Kharl faces a simulacra of his mother and father, dressed in full paladin armour, along with the temples guardian drake, Brine. Lorna assaults the guardians from the rafters, killing Brine with a single arrow through the skull, and weakening Kharls mother to the point that Urlex could easily finish her with a vine-whip. In a vengeful rage, Kharl obliterates the simulacra of his father with a necrotic blast.</p><p>Sensing his grandfather in the next room, Kharl leaves the temple and enters the caldera of the islands volcano, where he finds his grandfather imprisoned in a pillar of salt. While they reunite, Lorna and Urllex quickly peruse Kharl the Elders study, finding amongst the hundred of blank tomes a couple of powerful scrolls.</p><p>Kharl the Elder reveals that while he has ascended, the primal spirit of Old Rhob is trapped on the material plane, unable to ascend without a ritual. Kharl tasks the party with finding Rhob, and taking him to Skypeircer temple, for which they will need a map, and then conducting a ritual to allow him to ascend properly. Kharl the Elder then leaves for the astral reflection of skypeircer temple, telling Kharl that everything would be explained when he knows it is safe to do so.</p><p>As the sun rises, the party returns to the ocean, and re-enters the bullywug grove through the reflection in the water.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 10: The White Iron Company]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-10-The-White-Iron-Company</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-10-The-White-Iron-Company"/>
        <updated>2017-06-18T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kyuss steals Zyn’s skull and slinks off with Varyk to confront and blackmail the buried drow – Xullraen T’orgh. Kyuss uses the skull to threaten her, indicating it would interfere with her ooze form, and then says that by killing Zyn, the two are even. Kyuss then destroys Xullraen’s body, apparently happy that his work has been done.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kyuss steals Zyn’s skull and slinks off with Varyk to confront and blackmail the buried drow – Xullraen T’orgh. Kyuss uses the skull to threaten her, indicating it would interfere with her ooze form, and then says that by killing Zyn, the two are even. Kyuss then destroys Xullraen’s body, apparently happy that his work has been done.</p><p>While Kharl finds documents confirming his grandfathers death was at the hands of these people, Dakarai accidently connects with the conciousness of Recrentius by touching Zyn’s scrying machine. Unfortunately, before they can experiment with the machine any further, Urllex collapses the scrying room while trying to pry a fake emerald out of a statue in the room.</p><p>Leading the party out of the dungeon, Kharl accidently walks straight into a dangerous situation, leading to Lorna being separated from the rest of the party. While the party recover, Lorna re-appears as a captive of a group of hobgoblins, lead by the disabled goblin seer, Kugs. Kugs approaces Urllex and touches her slave-mark, giving her a vision of the future where she stands defiant before a vast army of Alu-Tel, supported by all matter of beast races. Kugs tells Urllex that for the vision to come true, the orcs must have Lightbringer to unite them. Kharl agrees to hand over the weapon, and Lorna is returned. The hobgoblins go deeper into the caves, seeking the underdark.</p><p>Lorna leads the group out of the mines, where they manage to spot members of the White Iron Company, who seem to have followed the party to the Spellforge and have captured their horses. Lorna recognises the armour – these are the people that killed her family. Restraining themselves, Urlex and Kharl go down to meet with the commander, and sign documents under duress handing over salvage right of the Spellforge. Urlex puts druid sign on the document, indicating that they should be voided, as Dakarai makes a break for the trees as a distraction.</p><p>The party pretends to leave, and camps. Dakarai runs home to Phandalin and gets support from Hudson to retake the spellforge. Lorna gains the support of the salt-marsh bullywugs by communing with nature.</p><p>After a few days of watching the White Iron Company pull the spellforge apart, the party takes the excavation crew by suprise, splitting them in half at the entrance, and taking the exterior group captive. A second group arrives and are taken out by Lorna and her bullywugs. Sensing that they might not make it out alive, the captives make a break for it when Kharl, Dakarai and Urllexin are distracted by a trained Bulette.</p><p>The second group of soliders make a break for the secondary exit. Dakarai and Hudson hold off most of them, but a pair of soldiers escape back to their base of operations.</p><p>The party, aided by the bullywugs and Crossroad Knights, prepare for battle.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 9: The Black Spider]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-9-The-Black-Spider</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-9-The-Black-Spider"/>
        <updated>2017-05-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The voice in Darakrai’s head reveals itself to be the spectral guardian Glorba, created years ago to guard the spellforge from attack. Varyk disguises himself as Glorba’s master, Erik, and convinces Glorba that his job is done, and releases him from his bonds.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The voice in Darakrai’s head reveals itself to be the spectral guardian Glorba, created years ago to guard the spellforge from attack. Varyk disguises himself as Glorba’s master, Erik, and convinces Glorba that his job is done, and releases him from his bonds.</p><p>Exploring the spellforge, the party discovers two potent artifacts, the mace Lightbringer and an enchanted breastplate. They are also able to briefly enchant their weapons and armour, using the low flames of the spellforge itself.</p><p>Moving onwards, the party makes their way through a breached wall into a natural cavern that opens into a vast underwater ocean, finding the few abandoned boats left behind by Jaitus Kalo’s war party 20 years ago. Amongst the moldy supplies in the old boats, the party finds a number of looted trinkets, along with a real prize – a magical flying broom.</p><p>Climbing up to the west, the party observes a group of hobgoblins being watched over by a drow that Varyk recognises. Dakarai brings the loose rocks down upon the hobgoblins in an earthquake, and the party overpowers and restrains the drow, who reveals themselves to be another doppelganger. Not wanting to take any chances with the drow reincarnating and warning others, Kharl buries them alive under the rocks.</p><p>To the west lies a grand set of doors. Varyk, who can read all languages, identifies this room as being the Scrying Chamber, which Dakarai notes has never been mentioned in any books about the Spellforge. From within, Dakarai senses many bodies and also vast machinery.</p><p>Kharl puts two-and-two together, and determines that the people who killed his grandfather must have determined his location using this device. He immediately kicks the door in, surprising Zyn Coberal, the Black Spider, who is making notes on the far side of the scrying device – a massive, sand-covered disk, slowly being raked by cycling clockwork instruments .</p><p>Kharl, to the Spider’s fury, immediately summons a massive gust of wind, knocking sand and papers everywhere. As the party rushes in, dark shapes begin to drop for the ceiling, firing sticky black masses down at the party, who dodge and weave around them. While Lorna, Varyk and Urllexin deal to the descending tendrils, Dakarai and Kharl approach the Spider and his bodyguards, who summons darkness to shroud him. Using his tremorsense, Dakarai kills the hobgoblin guards in the pitch darkness, while Kharl is compelled by Zyn to hit himself in the face with his warhammer, which he does with gusto.</p><p>Lorna and Varyk take out half of the tendrils, but the last two overwhelm Urllexin. Rushing to help, Dakarai kills one, but is drenched with acid and poison by the other, and immediately attempts to flee on his broom, but is shot out of the air by the fleeing Zyn.</p><p>In a moment of religious zeal, Kharl bursts from the darkness, rushing the dark mass engulfing Urllexin, obliterating it with a thunderous rebuke, while at the same time engulfing Zyn in a blast of holy light, stripping him back half to his bones.</p><p>Stepping from behind a column, Lorna calmly skewers Zyn through the eye with her rapier, ending the fight. While Kyuss cackles in Varyk’s ear at the victory, Kharl stabilises and heals the party. As the party celebrates their victory, Lorna is suprised by the news that she just killed the Black Spider.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 8: The Highhaven Spellforge]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-8-The-Highhaven-Spellforge</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-8-The-Highhaven-Spellforge"/>
        <updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With Gundren rescued, the party makes their way back to Old Owl Well. When they return to the camp, Kharl is finally able to deliver his letter, which Gundren tells him to read to the group…]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With Gundren rescued, the party makes their way back to Old Owl Well. When they return to the camp, Kharl is finally able to deliver his letter, which Gundren tells him to read to the group…</p><hr><p>Gundren,</p><p>Last night I felt Old Rhob die, finally consumed by the maelstrom. The world does not mourn him – he has been gone for too long, and few remember him.</p><p>The seals we put in place to prevent this have been cracked, one by one, despite what I know to be your best efforts. I have felt the eyes of a diviner upon me, and I fear that it will only be a matter of time before some agent or another comes for me.</p><p>The plan is not working.</p><p>I know that you have always considered me rash, and impatient, and I respect that your long life gives you greater perspective. But here, at the end of my days, and with knives waiting for me in the night, I call you to action, before it is too late.</p><p>Kaz and Urzoth are gone. I am old and frail before my time. We have no heirs fit to carry on our duty. I fear that which we seek to contain has weakened us, has leeched our power from us, our bloodlines, our totems and our gods. We need to accept that this corruption is unique – it cannot be contained, and we must act to destroy it.</p><p>This will be our last correspondence. I will see this letter delivered, and then I intend to buy you some time by doing something drastic. I’m sure you wouldn’t approve.</p><p>Give my love to Lillin,</p><p>Kharl</p><hr><p>The next morning, a pair of elvish knights, a paladin and cleric of Tymora, arrive at <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/old-owl-well">Old Owl Well</a>, greeting them and asking them for directions to Agatha. Though Kharl is suspicious, the party leads the paladin to Agatha, and successfully extracts the location of Bojangles spellbook from the banshee – mislabeled, within the library at Highhaven. Having completed their mission, the knights offer to return Gundren to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/phandalin">Phandalin</a>, allowing the party to make their way directly to the Spellforge, now that they have the map.</p><p>Gundren reveals that he had simply sought out the Spellforge to find a tome that he believed would help him, and he was completely surprised by the Black Spider and the ferocity of his attacks. He tells the party that there must be something else within the Spellforge, something that is worth spending enormous quantities of resources on obtaining.</p><p>Parting ways, the party makes their way to the Spellforge, finding the caved in entrance after a couple of days of traveling overland. Entering the forge via a hidden fissure that had been created by earthquakes, the party sneaks their way through the old mining tunnels that criss-cross the outer edge of the old settlement, guided by Kharl’s magic and hidden by Urllex’s, until they find themselves on the other side of the caved in entrance.</p><p>Lorna clears the way forward, killing ghouls from the shadows, and they find that the undead hiding in the entrance of the cave have fled further into the complex, shying away from light shafts to the outside that Dakarai had cleared earlier.</p><p>Avoiding the main cavern of the complex, the party takes a detour into a fungus filled cavern, which Dakarai and Urllex determine to be poisonous. Varyk teleports Lorna and Urllexin across, while Dakarai  carefully climbs across the ceiling, using his earth attunement to find footholds in the rock. Blessing and warding himself, Kharl simply runs through the spores, managing to completely avoid the poison.</p><p>On the other side of the cavern, the party finds themselves in a beautiful, crystal studded cave that gives the illusion of the night sky, within which stands two structures. Entering the first one, the party angers a powerful wraith, and though they defeat it, it almost kills Kharl, and Dakarai is forced to bring the roof down on the wraith to scatter it, burying any treasure that may have lain within.</p><p>Moving on to the second structure, Dakarai attempts to stealthily approach the front door, but he is detected by some kind of psychic presence residing inside, which warns him against entering the spellforge…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 7: Escape from Cragmaw Castle]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-7-Escape-from-Cragmaw-Castle</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-7-Escape-from-Cragmaw-Castle"/>
        <updated>2016-12-14T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a brief discussion, the party decides that the dangers that lurk behind the curtain are too dangerous to deal with directly, so Varyk leads Kharl and Urllexin around the long way, intimidating his way through a banquet hall overseen by a goblin chef with a power complex.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a brief discussion, the party decides that the dangers that lurk behind the curtain are too dangerous to deal with directly, so Varyk leads Kharl and Urllexin around the long way, intimidating his way through a banquet hall overseen by a goblin chef with a power complex.</p><p>The group reunites in a small corridor with a barred exit that leads to the outside of the castle. Unbarring the exit, Urllexin and Lorna split away bring the cart around for a quick exit, while the others go deeper into the castle.</p><p>After swiftly dealing to the hobgoblin guards, Dakarai and Kharl hide in the shadows while Varyk comes face to face with King Grol and his guest; the “Black Spider.” Grol believes that Varyk is in league with the Spider and leads him in. The Spider is not fooled, but allows the scene to unfold.</p><p>Varyk identifies the Spider as his one time employer Zyn Coborel, and <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/Kyuss/new">Kyuss</a> warns Varyk against acting rashly, as something about the situation is off.</p><p>Grol reveals that he has been working with Zyn in return for the enchanted mace “Lightbringer.” When Zyn asks for more manpower to help him excavate the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-highhaven-spellforge">Spellforge</a>, Grol becomes angry, revealing that he has already gone above and beyond his part of the deal, capturing Gundren (who Varyk identifies as an unconscious heap in the corner) and obtaining his map.</p><p>After toying with Varyk for a moment, Zyn suddenly flips the table and begins to make a move at Varyk. In that instant, Dakarai and Kharl leap out of hiding and launch a surprise attack against Grol and his wolf, who had been sleeping at the fire.</p><p>Surprised, Zyn takes Gundren hostage and drags him to the window, knife to his throat. Kharl uses a spell Gundren, reviving him  and then closes the distance on Zyn. Gundren uses this opportunity to escape from Zyn’s grip, crawling on his hands and knees away from the fight.</p><p>Zyn’s throat deforms and swells in an entirely alien way, and the drow spits acid onto the fleeing Gundren, badly burning the dwarf and leaving him twitching and writhing on the floor. Kharl hits Zyn with his mace in retaliation, and is surprised when the hammer merely sinks into his body – the drows flesh is like tar.</p><p>While Dakarai single handedly handles Grol and his wolf, Varyk and Kharl close in on Zyn, dousing him with fire and finally killing him with a blast of holy energy. In death, Zyn’s body melts almost completely – Kyuss appears to Varyk and informs him sagely that if that was a real guy, you would have expected to see bones in there.</p><p>Stabilising Gundren and recovering the map from beneath Grol’s filthy mattress, the party leaves the castle via their escape route, towards the waiting Lorna and Urllexin, who lead them away from the castle and through the checkpoint at the outer wall, the grounds now peppered with dead goblins.</p><p>The party makes their way back to the hideaway overlooking the castle, and hunkers down to wait out the storm.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 6: Cragmaw Castle]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-6-Cragmaw-Castle</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-6-Cragmaw-Castle"/>
        <updated>2016-11-23T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party spends some time recuperating at Old Owl Well. Varyk, banished to an otherworldly waiting room by his demonic patron, is summarily returned with a mission – find the Drow responsible for attacking him and teleporting Varyk to Espis in the first place. After Dakarai identifies from a scroll that the priest they had defeated was preparing the outpost for a ritual of displacement, the party spent some time clearing the symbols and reversing the spell.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party spends some time recuperating at Old Owl Well. Varyk, banished to an otherworldly waiting room by his demonic patron, is summarily returned with a mission – find the Drow responsible for attacking him and teleporting Varyk to Espis in the first place. After Dakarai identifies from a scroll that the priest they had defeated was preparing the outpost for a ritual of displacement, the party spent some time clearing the symbols and reversing the spell.</p><p>The party stumbles upon a boarded up entrance to the keep below Old Owl Well, and finds signs of a struggle and a shattered mechanism. After reactivating the mechanism, the party opens an iron portal, revealing a chute that falls down into inky, wet darkness. After much deliberation, the party closes the portal, closes the entrance, and leaves a note for future adventurers to keep clear.</p><p>The party leaves Old Owl Well to meet with the banshee Agatha, travelling down a rough path hewn into the side of a canyon into the heavily wooded lowlands.</p><p>Upon meeting with Agatha, Kharl fails to calm the banshee, and in a fit of righteousness, banishes Agatha from her home. While the party wondered what to do next, Agatha returned, conjuring up images of destruction and causing all but Dakarai and Kharl to flee. Dakarai watches on in horror as Kharl is almost killed by Agatha’s shriek, before the banshee and her home disappear entirely.</p><p>Feeling a pull towards the nearby swamp by the roots in her rucksack, Lorna and Urllexin lead the party down into the nearby swamp, where they come across signs of destruction, strikingly similar to the damage done to Lorna’s homeland. The party makes contact with a tribe of Bullywugs, who’s town was destroyed, and Urllexin manages to strike up a conversation with the tribes Druid, who imparts that the town was destroyed by armoured mercenaries wielding silvered weapons. Lorna gifts the roots in her bag to the swamp, growing a new cluster of mangroves to the delight and relief of the Bullywugs. One of the trees gifts Lorna the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/flowering-bow">Flowering Bow</a>, as a sign of thanks.</p><p>Leaving the swamp, the party spends another night at Old Owl Well, in preparation for a two day journey to Cragmaw Castle. After an uneventful trip along the edge of the canyon, the party arrives at the castle just as a storm is beginning to strike. Posing as an agent of the Black Spider, Varyk leads Urllex and Kharl into the castle as prisoners, while Lorna and Dakarai stealthily scale the side of the castle. Unguarded and inside the castle, the party quietly makes their way inside, finding the sword of <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/hudson">Hudson Abadeir</a> in the process.</p><p>Hearing chanting coming from inside the old chapel, Kharl leads a savage attack on a group of Goblin worshippers lead by the Goblin priest Lhupo, while Dakarai and Lorna make their way along the walls of the castle and into a precarious ruined tower on the western side.</p><p>Both groups are now inside the castle, separated from each other by a blacked-out section of the former chapel, the party gears up for an attack on something that they can hear lurking in the darkness…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 5: Arborox]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-5-Arborox</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-5-Arborox"/>
        <updated>2016-09-09T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party arrives at Arborox, finding it abandoned except for zombies and monsters. In an abandoned inn, the Brown Horse, Dakarai identified a symbol of Xaviara hewn into the floor, indicating that the town had fallen prey to absolute despair, desperately trying anything to stay bound together after the collapse.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party arrives at Arborox, finding it abandoned except for zombies and monsters. In an abandoned inn, the Brown Horse, Dakarai identified a symbol of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/xaviara">Xaviara</a> hewn into the floor, indicating that the town had fallen prey to absolute despair, desperately trying anything to stay bound together after the collapse.</p><p>Finally tracking down the druid Reidoth, the party made some concerning discoveries – Kharl, that his god Rhobsarendor died long ago, raising the question of whom he was communing with,  Lorna, that the skull she has been carrying around was in fact a construct, a result of modern, state-of-the-art runecraft, and that Urllexin had suppressed memories of being sent to the beast coast because she showed promise as a druid. The party also received the final piece of the map required to hunt down Cragmaw castle, and hopefully rescue Rockseeker.</p><p>Unsure of their capacity to defeat the creatures of Arborox and drive off its resident dragon, the party struck out for Cragmaw castle, with the aim of stopping off at Old Owl Well along the way. Arriving at the abandoned watchtower, the party ran afoul of a priest of the Bloody Light and his undead servants, who was at the watchtower to somehow ‘claim’ it for the church.</p><p>Immediately striking, the party successfully defeated the priest, though his undead servants (and their disembodied, scuttling hands) were a tough adversary. Dakarai pulled a book off the priests body that seemed to describe the ritual he was undertaking in detail. Taking a brief rest in the abandoned tower, the party readied themselves for their next task – communing with the banshee Agatha.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 4: Glasstaff]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-4-Glasstaff</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-4-Glasstaff"/>
        <updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Without warning, Varyk’s demonic patron captures him and pulls his struggling body through a flaming portal, at the same time plucking the parties memory of him out of thier heads.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Without warning, Varyk’s demonic patron captures him and pulls his struggling body through a flaming portal, at the same time plucking the parties memory of him out of thier heads.</p><p>Unperturbed, the rest of the party breaks down the door to Glasstaff’s labratory, finding it deserted. Determining that Glasstaff has fled, the party tracks him to the entrance of the dungeon, where he is swiftly disabled by Lorna.</p><p>Kharl delivers the unconcious wizard to Hudson, who reveals that the wizard is Iarno Albrek, a wizard of the Crossroad Knights that Hudson was sent to seek out. Meanwhile, the party, searching for Qelline Alderleaf and her son, engages the Nothic, unaware of the deal the creature made with Varyk. Quick thinking by Darakrai and Lorna saw the creature crushed under a rock, deep in a ravine, where the party also discovered a chache of treasure, including an enchanted Laventius family sword of considerable power.</p><p>Hearing voices calling out from an unexplored passage, Kharl follows a corridor into the old Laventius crypt, where he is attacked by three skeletons. He manages to turn two of them, but is incapacitated by the last, before the rest of the party returned to rescue him.</p><p>Exploring the crypt, the party found a hidden prison and saved the trapped halfling and her son, who Lorna helped return home. Meanwhile, Urllexin and Dakarai searched Glasstaffs belongings, finding evidence of his betrayal, and returned this evidence to Hudson.</p><p>Hudson, overwhelmed by the discovery of Iarno’s betrayal and the revelation that he was the heir to the Laventius Estate (from a note found within the recently discovered sword), tasked the party with hunting down the rest of the hobgoblins and putting an end to the Black Spider.</p><p>With a few leads to follow, the party bought two horses and a cart, and headed out of town, making for Arborox, to hunt down the druid Lorna has been searching for.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 3: Into the Laventius Estate]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-3-Into-the-Laventius-Estate</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-3-Into-the-Laventius-Estate"/>
        <updated>2016-08-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party returns to Phandalin with their hobgoblin prisoner, and spends the day in training, rest and recuperation. Varyk spends this time on an information gathering expedition, and overhears a few of the Redbrands plotting to silence him that night.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party returns to Phandalin with their hobgoblin prisoner, and spends the day in training, rest and recuperation. Varyk spends this time on an information gathering expedition, and overhears a few of the Redbrands plotting to silence him that night.</p><p>The party sets up an ambush, capturing three of these attackers and killing one. During the fighting, Dakarai, a lost vagabond, warns Urllexin to approaching enemies, and is welcomed into the group. Clues on the bodies of the prisoners lead the party to discover that the mayor was killed at some point earlier in the night.</p><p>The next morning, interrogation of the prisoners leads the party to discover that the Redbrands are hiding out beneath the Laventius Estate, to which they find two entrances. Qelline Alderleaf and her son being kidnapped raises the stakes, and the party enters the catacombs beneath the estate, fighting their way, room by room into the heart of the Redbrand base of operations (with the help of a few good berries).</p><p>While there are mostly humans and a few Bugbears camping in the ruins, Varyk does come across a dangerous lurking Nothic, and promises it the staff of the wizard Glasstaff if it leaves the party alone.</p><p>We left the party interrogating a drunk, just before discerning that the room they are in sits opposite Glasstaffs quarters.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 2: Arrival in Phandalin]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-2-Arrival-in-Phandalin</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-2-Arrival-in-Phandalin"/>
        <updated>2016-08-15T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party travels to Phandalin, chased for a while by Klarg and his goblins, before successfully arriving in the town and delivering the goods they were escorting and receiving their payment. They travel to the local inn for the night, where they hear a number of rumors and receive a number of opportunities;]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party travels to Phandalin, chased for a while by Klarg and his goblins, before successfully arriving in the town and delivering the goods they were escorting and receiving their payment. They travel to the local inn for the night, where they hear a number of rumors and receive a number of opportunities;</p><ul><li>Lorna followed up on a lead and found out from the halfling Qelline Alderleaf that the druid she has been searching for is currently living in the town of Arboron.</li><li>Sister Garaele asked Kharl to visit a banshee out at Old Owl Well, and gave him a comb to present as a gift.</li><li>The party found out about orcs raiding from the east, which there is a bounty on.</li><li>The party was asked to rid the town of the Redbrand faction by multiple parties. Varyk overheard from a group of members that the group answers to a wizard named Glassstaff and appears to answer to the Black Spider.</li><li>The party was asked by Hudson to maintain pressure on the goblin attackers, hunt down Grunden Rockseeker, find out what is going on and who is behind it, and find his sword, Laventius’ Bane.</li></ul><p>Before acting on any of these opportunities, the party waits until night and returns to the goblin hideout, with the intention of defeating Klarg and finding out where Grunden Rockseeker might be held. After a rough skirmish at the front of the cave (the goblins having set up more defensive structures in the previous day), the party reached a stalemate with Klarg, who had holed away in a well defended cave.</p><p>Divining from conversation and hints that the ‘Black Spider’ that Klarg serves might be a dark elf, Varyk tricks Klarg into believing that he is a friend,  and gets them to reveal that they came from a place called Cragmaw Castle. The ruse is discovered when Klarg’s wolf smells Urllexin, but before they can react, Varyk engulfs them all in flame, while Lorna and Urllexin shoot from the shadows.</p><p>Varyk stabilises Klarg and ties him up for further questioning, and the party loot his treasure chest and discover a lost shipment of supplies bound for Phandalin.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Espis Chapter 1: The Goblin Ambush]]></title>
        <id>Espis-Chapter-1-The-Goblin-Ambush</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Espis-Chapter-1-The-Goblin-Ambush"/>
        <updated>2016-08-10T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a variety of different reasons, and with different goals, a party of adventurers escorts a caravan of supplies to the town of Phandalin, where they hope to meet Gundren Rockseeker, a  guild leader and prospector.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For a variety of different reasons, and with different goals, a party of adventurers escorts a caravan of supplies to the town of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/phandalin">Phandalin</a>, where they hope to meet Gundren Rockseeker, a  guild leader and prospector.</p><p>Half a day from the town, they are ambushed by goblins, and find evidence that <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/hudson">Hudson Abadeir</a> of the Crossroad Knights has been captured and taken to a nearby hideout. Following tracks left by the goblins, <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/urllexin">Urllexin</a> leads the party to a cave entrance.</p><p><a href="/graveyard-world/characters/lorna">Lorna</a> scopes out the cave, leading to the capture and integration of a hapless goblin watchman, who tells them that Gundren has been kidnapped and taken to King Grol, who the goblins in the cave report to. The party also become aware that Hudson Abadeir is inside, held in the ‘eating cave’.</p><p>The party charges in, avoiding wolves and narrowly avoiding a water trap designed to repel intruders, and after a flawlessly executed ambush manages to rescue Hudson, who is furious at his capture and the loss of his sword,<a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/laventius-bane">Laventius’ Bane</a>. He offers the party a reward for getting him safely to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/phandalin">Phandalin</a>, and the party, exhausted and injured, agrees.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Aftermath]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Aftermath</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Aftermath"/>
        <updated>2016-07-30T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The events that happened in Arkenreln during the battle with Cherintanos and the Lich are muddy, but had a few obvious effects on the world at large.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The events that happened in Arkenreln during the battle with <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/cherintanos">Cherintanos</a> and the Lich are muddy, but had a few obvious effects on the world at large.</p><p>While the Lich was defeated, it appears that Cherintanos managed to ascend, becoming a shapeshifting, undead god that continues to be a source of fear for the entire world. Atrius, unwilling to let this stand, left on a journey to master a new form of shapeshifting and to find a way to destroy Cherintanos for good.</p><p>Gripped by religious ecstasy, the armies of Overcairn declared Recrentius the true ruler of Arkenreln and the High Prophet of the God of Bloody Light, and have since began transforming the realm into a religious state.</p><p>Arvahnt, disgusted by this turn of events, channeled the power of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-gnarl">The Gnarl</a> and severed Arkenreln’s connection to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-nameless-forest">the Nameless Forest</a>, returning it to the Outer Reaches, where she remains as it’s protector to this day.</p><p>Nobody quite knew what became of Eilyac, who seemed to be pulled into a dark portal at a pivotal point during the fighting, seconds after preventing the Lich from casting a dark spell on the lodestone of Overcairn. Many of those who were close to death during the fighting noted that they saw his grinning face in their dreams, seconds before being stabalised or healed.</p><p>Either through political or mystical means, the supplies of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-negative-energy-mines">Negative Energy</a> from Arkenreln dried up, meaning that anti-magical devices throughout the lodestone network quickly became far harder to maintain, leading to a golden age for arcane trickery.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Chapter 6: Retaking Overcairn]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Chapter-6-Retaking-Overcairn</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Chapter-6-Retaking-Overcairn"/>
        <updated>2014-09-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party returns to Overcairn, which is a city in chaos. The Caster of Shadows, a mysterious crime lord, has come out of hiding after the creation of the Tantail Tree destroyed the underground network her spies used to transport goods.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The party returns to Overcairn, which is a city in chaos. <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/the-caster-of-shadows">The Caster of Shadows</a>, a mysterious crime lord, has come out of hiding after the creation of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-tantail-tree">the Tantail Tree</a> destroyed the underground network her spies used to transport goods.</p><p>The party joins up with resistance fighters, defeats an ambush of the Caster’s shadows, and begins planning a counterattack to retake the castle that the Caster has made her home. While Recrentius whips Overcairn’s soldiers into a religious fervour and leads the army against the massed Shadows, the rest of the party sneaks into the castle in an attempt to cut off the head of the snake.</p><p>The party succeeds in their mission, and begins the process of readying the city for an undead invasion from beyond the fleshwastes.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highhaven-in-Solitude Chapter 2: All Problems Can Be Solved Permanently By Killing Gods With Almost No Provication]]></title>
        <id>Highhaven-in-Solitude-Chapter-2-All-Problems-Can-Be-Solved-Permanently-By-Killing-Gods-With-Almost-No-Provication</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Highhaven-in-Solitude-Chapter-2-All-Problems-Can-Be-Solved-Permanently-By-Killing-Gods-With-Almost-No-Provication"/>
        <updated>2014-09-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After successfully infiltrating Jaitus Kalo’s forces, the party, joined by a local druid, Vulptic, discover Kalo’s true plan. Kalo, who has rejected godhood, intends to break into the ice dome which acts as a portal to the realm of Xaviara created by the impact of the Abyssal Crown and use the power of his Lastember ring to steal the gods power for mankind.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After successfully infiltrating <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/kalo">Jaitus Kalo’s</a> forces, the party, joined by a local druid, Vulptic, discover Kalo’s true plan. Kalo, who has rejected godhood, intends to break into the ice dome which acts as a portal to the realm of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/xaviara">Xaviara</a> created by the impact of the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/abyssal-crown">Abyssal Crown</a> and use the power of his <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/lastember">Lastember</a> ring to steal the gods power for mankind.</p><p>Breaking away from Kalo’s forces after their ruse fails, the party escapes into the portal, finding themselves in a dense steamy jungle. At the center of the jungle, they find an ancient rusted city, suspended by chains over an abyss, and they crawl over it, enter the castle, and face a weakened Xaviara.</p><p>Humble Hank, previous wearer of the Abyssal Crown, breaks his mental chains to Xaviara and kills the god, ruining Kalo’s plans and destroying any influence that the crown still had upon him.</p><p>Upon leaving the city, the party was captured by, and quickly befriended by, a tribe of orcs that called the jungle home. After a night of feasting, the party partook in a hallucinogenic mixture designed to create a berserker wrath, and when they all came to they were on the front lines of a battle between the orc tribes and Jaitus Kalo’s forces.</p><p>The party dived into battle, eventually engaging Kalo himself. After an intense fight, Kalo, ceding defeat, swore vengeance on the party and accepted the godhood he had been rejecting, entering <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/ascension">Ascension</a>. Though worried for what this might mean in the future, the party celebrated their victory, and their recovery of the device Kalo was using to hold Highhaven’s lodestone portal closed.</p><p>The party returned to Highhaven, where connection to the outside world was re-established, and the party were revered as heroes.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Highhaven-in-Solitude Chapter 1: Two Men Fall From the Sky, Ruining Everything For Everyone]]></title>
        <id>Highhaven-in-Solitude-Chapter-1-Two-Men-Fall-From-the-Sky,-Ruining-Everything-For-Everyone</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Highhaven-in-Solitude-Chapter-1-Two-Men-Fall-From-the-Sky,-Ruining-Everything-For-Everyone"/>
        <updated>2014-08-07T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking the stillness of a cold, icy evening, Magicami and Humble Hank fall from the sky leaving great trails of fire in their wake. When they come to, they are alone in an icy wasteland, with no memory of recent events.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Breaking the stillness of a cold, icy evening, Magicami and Humble Hank fall from the sky leaving great trails of fire in their wake. When they come to, they are alone in an icy wasteland, with no memory of recent events.</p><p>Hours earlier, the sellsword <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/hudson">Hudson Abadeir</a>, knocked prone in a bloody ambush while working as a bodyguard in the city of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-portal-city-of-highhaven">Highhaven</a> witnesses a group of robed figures take control of the crystal lodestone at the center of the city, teleporting it from the subtropical Espis onto an unknown glacier.</p><p>After rescuing Magicami and Hank and leading them into the city, Hudson reports to the city council, who task him with hunting down a powerful amulet that is required for the lodestone to work, before the city freezes and starves. The trio scour the city, which is tearing itself apart looking for food, warmth, and someone to blame and eventually use a magical compass fashioned from Hudson’s ancestral sword to home in on the location of the magical amulet.</p><p>Travelling deep into the old keeps beneath Highhaven, the trio suprise, overpower and take the robes of a pair of powerful mages. Sneaking into what appears to be a base of operations, Magicami is terrified to recognise the powerful Archmage <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/kalo">Jaitus Kalo</a> as the leader of the mages. Maintaining their disguises, the trio load up a caravan with magical equipment and supplies and ride along with the group as they leave, carving a route deep into the ice that now surrounds the city.</p><p>After emerging from the icy tunnel, the party sees the caravans destination – a <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-crystal-spire">Crystal meteorite</a> that has crashed into the glacier not far from the city. A icy spire that seems to be rebuilding itself, even as they approach it…</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Chapter 5: Returning to Overcairn]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Chapter-5-Returning-to-Overcairn</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Chapter-5-Returning-to-Overcairn"/>
        <updated>2014-08-05T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Arvahnt awakens in the mountains one morning after a prophetic vision. Reciting it to the party, the group becomes concerned that a lich has revived the powerful chimeramancer Cherintanos with the intent of marching on Overcairn. Consulting the Book of Laws, Recrentius concludes from this that the phylactery Arvahnt possesses simply taps into a greater well of power concealed somewhere else, and makes a vow to destroy Cherintanos.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/graveyard-world/characters/arvahnt">Arvahnt</a> awakens in the mountains one morning after a prophetic vision. Reciting it to the party, the group becomes concerned that a lich has revived the powerful chimeramancer <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/cherintanos">Cherintanos</a> with the intent of marching on <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-portal-city-of-overcairn">Overcairn</a>. Consulting the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/book-of-laws">Book of Laws</a>, <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/recrentius">Recrentius</a> concludes from this that the phylactery Arvahnt possesses simply taps into a greater well of power concealed somewhere else, and makes a vow to destroy Cherintanos.</p><p>The party is cautious in returning directly to Overcairn, taking the opportunity to stop in the town of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/norge">Norge</a> to recuperate, forge new armour and weapons, and prepare. <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/eilyac">Eilyac</a> visits his old friend <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/randy">Silent Randy</a> with <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/atrius">Atrius</a> to learn all he can from the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/atlas-of-arkenreln">Atlas of Arkenreln</a>, and picks up the gist of the language after a couple of weeks of study. <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/sacer">Sacer the Irascible</a> uses the down time to drink, gamble and generally carouse around the run-down town, picking up rumours that Overcairn is in a bad state, overtaken by a criminal cartel run by the mysterious Caster of Shadows.</p><p>With the threat of Cherintanos looming, the party finishes their preparations and begins the long journey back to Overcairn, travelling overland to avoid bandits on the road. After a small skirmish with a trained Boarcupine on the main road, the way is clear to re-enter the city, and see what new dangers it holds.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Chapter 4: Rebinding the Book of Laws]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Chapter-4-Rebinding-the-Book-of-Laws</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Chapter-4-Rebinding-the-Book-of-Laws"/>
        <updated>2014-08-01T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In their quest to cleanse the library of the bloody god, Eilyac is killed, and unbeknown to the party makes a deal with Death that when the fate of Arkenreln is in the balance, Eilyac will act to cause destruction, or be forced to become Death himself.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In their quest to cleanse the library of the bloody god, Eilyac is killed, and unbeknown to the party makes a deal with Death that when the fate of Arkenreln is in the balance, Eilyac will act to cause destruction, or be forced to become Death himself.</p><p>Eventually, Azenkazahel is defeated, and Recrentius begins the long process of rebinding the Book of Laws. Recrentius rebels from the idea to add their own interpretation to the Laws, and doubles down on the Old Ways.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Chapter 3: Library of the Bloody God]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Chapter-3-Library-of-the-Bloody-God</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Chapter-3-Library-of-the-Bloody-God"/>
        <updated>2014-07-29T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Having completed her task, as promised Arvahnt takes Recrentius to Nink, who tells them that if they want a new  Book of Laws, they will need to travel to the Library of the God of Bloody Light, where a mighty press exists that will allow the book to be rebound.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Having completed her task, as promised Arvahnt takes Recrentius to Nink, who tells them that if they want a new  Book of Laws, they will need to travel to the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/library-of-the-god-of-bloody-light">Library of the God of Bloody Light</a>, where a mighty press exists that will allow the book to be rebound.</p><p>The party travels out of Arkenreln and into the wilds, braving bad weather and fierce monsters, eventually making their way into the library, which has been corrupted by a powerful chaos druid, <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/azenkazahel">Azenkazahel</a>, who is intent on the Book of Laws never being rebound.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Chapter 2: Planting the Seed]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Chapter-2-Planting-the-Seed</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Chapter-2-Planting-the-Seed"/>
        <updated>2014-07-22T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Atrius, Eilyac and Recrentius, celebrating at Filthy Brian’s in the days following the destruction of the wall of flesh, are approached by a stranger. She reveals herself to be Arvahnt, having returned to the city to fix the damage she witnessed Humble Hank and Magicami cause.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="/graveyard-world/characters/atrius">Atrius</a>, <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/eilyac">Eilyac</a> and <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/recrentius">Recrentius</a>, celebrating at <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/Filthy Brian's/new">Filthy Brian’s</a> in the days following the destruction of the wall of flesh, are approached by a stranger. She reveals herself to be <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/arvahnt">Arvahnt</a>, having returned to the city to fix the damage she witnessed <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/humble-hank">Humble Hank</a> and <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/magicami">Magicami</a> cause.</p><p>After witnessing the horror that befell the pair, Arvahnt had fled back to <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-nameless-forest">the forests of her youth</a> looking for guidance. There, she stumbled upon <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/nink-ferret-god-of-healing-and-restoration">Nink</a>, the ferret God of healing and restoration. Nink took her as a Disciple, presenting her with the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/velden-bow">Velden Bow</a> and a mystical seed before commanding her to return to Overcairn and purify the husk left by the wall of flesh.</p><p>After beseeching them to help her on her quest, Atrius, seeking to restore the balance of nature in the city, agrees to come. Recrentius is only convinced after Arvahnt promises to bring Recrentius to Nink, in the hope of finding a clue to the location of a new book.</p><p>The party travels underneath the city, fighting local bandits that make use of the tunnels, and eventually makes their way into an ancient flooded plaza, in the center of which is a petrified tree, their goal. Unfortunately, the ground is crawling with a hive of formians. Recrentius and Eilyac cause a distraction and lead the warriors away, while Arvahnt and Atrius make a run for the tree.</p><p>The tree is revealed to be protected by <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/mesphyr-chameleon-god-of-disguise-and-deceit">Mesphyr, the Chameleon God of Disguise and Deceit</a>, and planting the seed causes her spirit to be revitalised.</p><p>As the tree grows, the party battles the formian queen, and in the culmination of that fight, the growing tree breaks through into daylight, and begins to reclaim and decompose the husk of the Wall of Flesh, becoming <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-tantail-tree">the Tantail Tree</a>. In addition, the roots spread through the undercity, closing off the underground routes taken by slavers and thieves.</p><p>Oh, and I forgot to add, this whole time Eilyac was hauling around a massive carpet that he found because he was determined to sell it, regardless of how much irritation this caused.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Arkenreln Chapter 1: Wall of Flesh]]></title>
        <id>Arkenreln-Chapter-1-Wall-of-Flesh</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Arkenreln-Chapter-1-Wall-of-Flesh"/>
        <updated>2014-07-12T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Atrius and Eilyac, drinking at a local bar, are joined by the mysterious Paladin Recrentius, who has received visions of a horrifying event about to take place. Going outside, they see a city besieged by horrifying, gibbering flying crow monsters.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Atrius and Eilyac, drinking at a local bar, are joined by the mysterious Paladin Recrentius, who has received visions of a horrifying event about to take place. Going outside, they see a city besieged by horrifying, gibbering flying crow monsters.</p><p>Travelling to the edge of the city, they see an oncoming wall of flesh of unknown origin. Recrentius’s God tells them that they need to enter the wall and destroy its core. With the help of some local mages, the group makes their way into creature, which is covered in thousands of faces, all calling themselves <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/doug">Doug</a>.</p><p>After fighting their way through the guts of the creature, they find themselves in a ruined cathedral, which they realise is a area of <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/ascension">Ascension</a>. At the core of the temple, they find the ruined bodies of Magicami and Hank, bound together with the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/staff-of-visceral-integration">Staff of Visceral Integration</a> and the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/abyssal-crown">Abyssal Crown</a>. During the battle, Recrentius is delivered a mortal injury, and comes face-to-face with their god, the God Of Bloody Light. The god takes Recrentius’s book, but gives them life again, and tells them their true purpose – to rebind the Book of Laws and spread the word of God. Coming to,  Recrentius knocks the crown from the head of the monstrosity, and the crown, staff, Magicami and Hank are pulled into the void, bound together and screaming for eternity.</p><p>The party escapes the crumbling flesh wall, which has already begun to rot and calcify.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prologue Part 2: A Horrifying Magical Tragedy]]></title>
        <id>Prologue-Part-2-A-Horrifying-Magical-Tragedy</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Prologue-Part-2-A-Horrifying-Magical-Tragedy"/>
        <updated>2014-05-17T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Magicami and Arvahnt are joined by Humble Hank, a local thief, and accept a request by Mayor Eclectus to enter a nearby crypt in order to ask his dead father a simple question.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Magicami and Arvahnt are joined by Humble Hank, a local thief, and accept a request by <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/eclectus">Mayor Eclectus</a> to enter a nearby crypt in order to ask his dead father a simple question.</p><p>Lead astray by Hank, who has been coveting a treasure he has heard exists in the nearby ruins, the party diverts their journey and bumps into <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/doug">Doug the Chimeramancer</a>, a hapless wizard who is immediately charmed by Magicami.</p><p>Doug leads the party to a great ziggurat, but they are not alone – a number of powerful wizards have also made their way to the ziggurat in search of the treasure, revealed to be the powerful <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/abyssal-crown">Abyssal Crown</a>.</p><p>During the intense battle, Magicami, struggling with Doug, steals and in desperation activates the <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/staff-of-visceral-integration">Staff of Visceral Integration</a>. When he comes to, he has merged with Doug, into a horrible, two headed beast. Charming his second head into submission, Magicami rejoins the fray, only to be forced to use the staff again against the advancing <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/crowlord">Crowlord</a>. When he comes to, he has merged with the Crowlord, a horrifying three headed monstrosity that can fire crows from it’s chest.</p><p>Magicami uses a polymorph spell to disguise his horrifying exterior, and rejoins the party as they enter the now open zuggurat. Defeating the guardians of the temple, Hank immediately dons the Abyssal Crown, which burrows bolts into his head, fusing with him. As Hank screams, Magicami’s spell wears off, revealing his extra two heads, which scream.</p><p>The staff of Visceral Integration immediately responds to the presence of the Crown, and while Arvahnt flees, not looking back, Magicami and Hank are pulled together into a seething, ever growing mass of eyes, teeth, and flesh.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prologue Part 1: Shadows in Gallowdale]]></title>
        <id>Prologue-Part-1-Shadows-in-Gallowdale</id>
        <link href="https://your-docusaurus-test-site.com/graveyard-world/blog/Prologue-Part-1-Shadows-in-Gallowdale"/>
        <updated>2014-04-21T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a successful day of conning rich travellers out of their money, Magicami set out to get good and drunk at a local dive bar. There, he befriended Arvahnt, a young Vyln who had just left The Nameless Forest for the first time.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After a successful day of conning rich travellers out of their money, <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/magicami">Magicami</a> set out to get good and drunk at a local dive bar. There, he befriended <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/arvahnt">Arvahnt</a>, a young Vyln who had just left <a href="/graveyard-world/wikis/the-nameless-forest">The Nameless Forest</a> for the first time.</p><p>Leaving the bar, the pair were cornered by a gang of thugs. After an ungainly getaway attempt that left them both tangled on the ground, Magicami charmed the gang leader, convincing him to lead them to his boss, the <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/shadow">Shadow</a>.</p><p>Upon entering the back-room of the <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/shadow">Shadow’s</a> base of operations, the ruse fell apart, the charmed thugs shaken to awareness. Upon realising the danger they were in Arvahnt decided to shoot first and ask questions later, killing <a href="/graveyard-world/characters/shadow">Shadow</a> and two of his men.</p><p>After a tense hostage negotiation, Magicami managed to the convince the last of the thugs to leave town, the pair staggered back to the inn, pausing only to loot the lockbox.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Welch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>